<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>design on Ayushman Khazanchi</title>
    <link>https://akzn.me/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in design on Ayushman Khazanchi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akzn.me/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unhappy UX and Paytm</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/unhappy-ux-and-paytm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/unhappy-ux-and-paytm/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I returned to India I’d never used Paytm but I’d heard a lot about it. With an overnight &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2016_Indian_banknote_demonetisation&#34;&gt;demonetization&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.paytm.com/accepting-payments-from-your-customers-through-paytm-qr-code-is-easier-than-ever-13ed06d8a4ba&#34;&gt;scan-to-pay QR codes&lt;/a&gt; located everywhere, Paytm has become the most recognizable digital payments company in India. It is now a bank, a mall, and a financial service provider. But I struggled with Paytm for over a week trying to figure out how to use the app. This is what the home screen looks like when you first open it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids=&amp;ldquo;1801,1802,1806,1807,1808&amp;rdquo; columns=&amp;ldquo;5&amp;rdquo; size=&amp;ldquo;large&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clunky and overwhelming would be an understatement. The home screen scrolls further down quite a bit and is routinely interspersed with ads. There are numerous irrelevant things on it for a first time user. When you sign up the app registers your phone number as your login credential. However, to do any transactions you need to link your bank account which was the first big hurdle I ran into. There’s no prompt for this during sign-up and it’s not immediately evident where to do this. Tapping the standard Android menu icon (three horizontal lines in the top-left) produces a long list of actions for which I don’t have much context. I’d heard you have to “add money” to your Paytm wallet so I tap the first “recharge” option thinking it meant recharging your wallet and that it would prompt me to link a bank before recharging. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t it. I looked around some more but gave up on the app soon after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came back to it some days later and after a few more attempts finally learned that the bank account setup is reached through the smiley face in the top-right corner which is barely visible with all the other noise in the app. Even going to this profile section reveals a list of actions I have zero knowledge or context about (even today after months of use). One would think Paytm ought to ship a PDF guide to its user alongside the app download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;paytm-transactions-or-what-i-like-to-call-the-game-of-where-is-my-money&#34;&gt;Paytm Transactions, or what I like to call the game of &amp;lsquo;Where is My Money?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twice now I’ve lost money reloading Paytm through the Uber integration. Reloading PayTM wallet through Uber isn’t stable. This isn’t a network issue — something that is genuinely an issue in India. To book an Uber using Paytm you need a minimum balance in your wallet of Rs 325. When it’s below that Uber offers an integration to help you reload your balance. While doing this the transaction failed for me in the processing stage. This led to the money getting debited from my bank account but not showing up in the Paytm wallet. To Paytm’s credit, they are quick to confirm failed transactions and immediately informed me via text. Once they were able to confirm that the amount had been debited from my account they sent me a confirmation message. However, even though the transaction was confirmed by Paytm, the balance credited in the wallet didn’t reflect the correct amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1794&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;345&amp;rdquo;]&lt;img src=&#34;images/IMG_20180315_233135_767-544x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image showing a text message with Paytm balance short of Rs. 350&#34;&gt; Paytm balance short of Rs. 350[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To raise this issue I ran into another conundrum. What category does this issue fit in? It’s not in any of the following: &lt;em&gt;Managing my Paytm account&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Recharge and Bill Payments&lt;/em&gt;,  &lt;em&gt;Fund Transfer Issues&lt;/em&gt;. Most surprisingly, it&amp;rsquo;s not even under &lt;em&gt;Adding money to wallet&lt;/em&gt; which is exactly what it&amp;rsquo;s doing (reloading money in your wallet). I found the transaction listed under &lt;em&gt;Payments using Wallet&lt;/em&gt; where there is a separate tab for “Added”. This list seems to be entirely different from the list of transactions located under the &lt;em&gt;Adding money to wallet&lt;/em&gt; option listed above even though from an end-user perspective both are doing the same thing. It doesn’t make sense why half of my transactions for adding money to the Paytm wallet would be in different sections varying on how the money was added (through Paytm vs third-party integration).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further I found out that if you run into the peculiar case where your transaction went through successfully but your updated balance is incorrect, there seems to be no way to reach Paytm to correct this. The &amp;ldquo;suggestion&amp;rdquo; I get from their support channel is simply to go back and check my balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids=&amp;ldquo;1796,1797,1810,1798&amp;rdquo; columns=&amp;ldquo;4&amp;rdquo; size=&amp;ldquo;large&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(At least I haven’t figured out their UI enough to know how to do this so if you know please guide me.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a lot about such apps offering unhappy and irksome user experiences. I’ve had a similar experience in the past while trying to get a refund from Uber but at least in that case I was dealing with a customer service rep. I don’t even know how to try with Paytm’s preset responses other than to reach out over social media which is far from a viable support option for most people in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In India, where large swathes of the population are now reliant on digital solutions like Paytm to combat earlier issues of demonetization, financial access, and exclusivity, this messy UX coupled with the hard-to-reach customer support end up isolating the people from the service. The problems of transactions may not be frequent though they &lt;a href=&#34;https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/companies/transaction-issues-on-paytm-continue/articleshow/56141117.cms&#34;&gt;exist in numbers&lt;/a&gt; but the overall confusing experience is not &lt;a href=&#34;https://telecomtalk.info/paytm-customer-issue/123126/&#34;&gt;uncommon&lt;/a&gt;. The person who runs the lunch cafeteria at my workplace at Oracle no longer accepts Paytm. He lost Rs. 1000 in a transaction that showed successful on the customer’s phone but never ended up getting credited to his account. Unable to get his money back or figure out how to raise his issue he stopped accepting Paytm altogether. Who do you go to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confusion creates room for ambiguity which in turn reduces trust, and trust is arguably the most important criteria for a financial services company. Paytm can maybe afford this inconvenience right now as there is no equal player in the industry as yet. BHIM and Google Tez have nowhere near the same penetration while Whatsapp payments is still in beta. Frustrating experiences such as these that should be easy to resolve for a company like Paytm end up causing a lack of trust in the technology and in digital solutions in general. And a lack of trust in a service where there is high dependency (everyone needs to transfer money) results in customers jumping ship to where they get better service. Or at least products that don&amp;rsquo;t further confuse them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have yet to see Whatsapp payments in action but I&amp;rsquo;ve heard people mention its simplicity. Like BHIM it is built on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cashlessindia.gov.in/upi.html&#34;&gt;Unified Payments Interface (UPI)&lt;/a&gt;[1] so there is also no need for an intermediary &amp;ldquo;wallet&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; money moves directly between accounts. Once Whatsapp payments rolls out country-wide it will become the biggest direct competitor to Paytm simply on the merit of its large user base. Then it will likely come down to which service provides a more intuitive and comfortable experience to the customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Paytm also has a Paytm BHIM UPI option now which offers a different way to pay than the regular payment option causing further confusion as to why there are two different options on the home screen to do the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts on Using the iPhone</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/some-thoughts-on-using-the-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/some-thoughts-on-using-the-iphone/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the iPhone 6S for about six months now. I made the switch from a Google Nexus 5 which was, in my opinion, the best Android phone to have come out in its time. With Google better defining and standardizing their material design philosophy it&amp;rsquo;s a great time to switch over to Android. Over the last few months I&amp;rsquo;ve grown to like the iPhone but I find something still amiss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to try and jot down a few thoughts on where, having switched from Android to iPhone, I found myself frustrated by the Apple experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home Screen / App Menu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first and foremost is the Home Screen. I&amp;rsquo;ve long favored the separation of the home screen from the app menu in Android. This way, in Android, you can add a bunch of favorite apps to the home screen if you want but also have the option of keeping it entirely app-free. Apple doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow an empty home screen and all my apps are present there whether I want them or not. Sometimes this feels like too much noise as soon as you unlock the phone. If I want to keep just my favorites on the main screen, I have to move all the other apps to the second screen (to the right). This is the way I have it right now but if you don&amp;rsquo;t organize well eventually you&amp;rsquo;ll end up having three home screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Folders&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Android has a separate App Screen there isn&amp;rsquo;t a &lt;em&gt;pressing&lt;/em&gt; need to create folders on the home screen. I don&amp;rsquo;t like folders at all but one can still do it in Android. The apps on my iPhone&amp;rsquo;s second screen are in folders only because those are junk apps Apple pre-loaded on to the phone and some I use as rarely as once a month. Also because with Apple if you want to create any kind of semblance in your life and maintain your apps only on two screens, you&amp;rsquo;ll inevitably have to create folders. The issue arises when you&amp;rsquo;re switching from one app in a folder to another app in a different folder, which if you&amp;rsquo;re not used to using the home button every time, gets really really awkward. Assuming you start inside the folder, the other app is still three clicks away - one to go back to the home screen, one to open the second folder, one to click on the app. (Four if your app is on the second screen (swipe) inside the folder.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use case for this on Android is simpler. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you start in a folder. One click to home screen, one click to open the menu, scroll to the app, and one click to get in. There is also the hard/soft back button and all apps are in the same hierarchy once you&amp;rsquo;re in the menu. This was not the case in Lollipop, I think, where the menu went from left to right and you had to swipe each time for a new page. Naturally, people complained and it was reverted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI Flow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I deeply miss the back button. Nothing will ever convince me that placing a soft button all the way to the top-left of the screen is a better idea than providing a hard/soft back button on the bottom left. The swipe gesture from the left edge of the screen is awkward as hell when you&amp;rsquo;re too far into the rabbithole and have to go back six pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notifications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had some apps (especially the default messaging app) on the iPhone show a notification on the lock screen but once you unlock the phone (not swiping on the app) the notifications disappear and don&amp;rsquo;t show up in the panel. They only show up as the numbers over the icon at that point. Not sure why only some apps do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In iOS, if a notification shows up in the panel but I check the notification by directly going to the app and not tapping on the notification itself the ideal workflow should involve the notification in the panel also disappearing. However, the iPhone continues showing the notification in the panel for something that I&amp;rsquo;ve already checked in the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Android if you bypass the notification panel and directly open the app containing the notification the notification in the panel also disappears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work email account (Exchange) does not ever show notifications either on the lock screen or notifications panel. There is only the notification sound and the vibration and the icon count. No actual notification information. If by chance I get the notification when my phone is unlocked then it shows up as a banner notification for a few seconds but never when it&amp;rsquo;s locked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The battery has been great on the iPhone. Granted I&amp;rsquo;ve only had it for about six months so it&amp;rsquo;s fairly new but it&amp;rsquo;s been beating my Android by a few hours at least. However, on the flipside, it&amp;rsquo;s also turned off on me at 15 % - 17 % multiple times when I&amp;rsquo;ve refused to turn on Low Power Mode. When it did turn off, it acted as if it was completely drained and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t turn on at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CalDav / Corporate Integration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the big reasons why I decided to switch to the iPhone for a while. The corporate sync is seamless in most cases. My work email syncs (despite the notifications), my calendar syncs and allows me to accept/decline meeting invites, and I can watch WebEx presentations from my phone as well (though I don&amp;rsquo;t usually use this). The calendar sync itself is a big plus for me as I can&amp;rsquo;t live without a calendar (I&amp;rsquo;d forget everything). Android dropped CalDav support for some reason and so I&amp;rsquo;ve never been able to get my work calendar on to Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exterior&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The metal body of the iPhone is vastly superior to the plastic of the Nexus phones. This is something that has definitely impressed me. The exterior design of the iPhone is amazing, and you can tell the quality apart. In fact, if I switch back to Android finding a phone with a metal body will be pretty high on the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>