<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>food on Ayushman Khazanchi</title>
    <link>https://akzn.me/tags/food/</link>
    <description>Recent content in food on Ayushman Khazanchi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 01:27:20 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akzn.me/tags/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chorizo Tacos</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/food/lappis-meals/chorizo-tacos/chorizo-tacos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 01:27:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/food/lappis-meals/chorizo-tacos/chorizo-tacos/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/food/lappis-meals/chorizo-tacos/images/chorizo-tacos.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;chorizo-tacos&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; height=&#34;50%&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Learned in One Week of Zero Carbs</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/what-i-learned-in-one-week-of-zero-carbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/what-i-learned-in-one-week-of-zero-carbs/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Monday (Jan. 11th) I decided to quit eating carbs for one week. My first encounter with this was a couple of years ago, sitting on a family friend&amp;rsquo;s couch, reading about Djokovic&amp;rsquo;s diet that propelled him, within a year, to the top rank. All he did was quit gluten completely and found himself getting stronger everyday. Just one change in diet having that big an effect made me a little skeptical but it stuck around in the back of my mind. Leading up to last week, I&amp;rsquo;d been reading a lot about the effects of certain food groups on the body. Carbs just stood out as the one group that a lot of people had reduced and felt noticeable improvements with. Now, I had no obvious reason to quit carbs. I&amp;rsquo;m not trying to lose weight. I&amp;rsquo;m generally healthy and I tend to eat healthier, home-cooked food more than eating outside. I just wanted to see how much it really affected my body. One of the only triggers beforehand was that I was frequently tired, not only after a full work day but also many times during it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read a lot about how people had reduced their carb intake, anywhere from 100 gm. to 200 gm. a day, and seen noticeable improvements. I figured it&amp;rsquo;d be a pain to keep calculating before each meal how many grams I had left for the day so I decided to go nuclear. For the sake of removing any calculations I decided to do zero carbs for the whole week. Also to ease up on the complexity I focused only on complex-sugar carbs - any kind of breads, pasta, cereal, noodles, rice, sugar, cookies, brownies, dried fruits, etc. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t snack much so most of these weren&amp;rsquo;t a big issue for me. But when you&amp;rsquo;re eating outside at least 4-5 times a week you realize pretty fast how impractical it is to stick to zero carb diets outside your own cooking. To compound that, rice or some kind of bread (roti/paratha/naan) is almost a staple for most Indian meals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/carbs-carbs-everywhere.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first two days took a little getting used to. I experienced a minor headache the entire day on my first day. I figured it was because of the lesser calories I was now eating so I upped the protein in my breakfast the next day. The headache was a lot less noticeable the second day and completely gone by the third. My eating out is generally restricted to going out for lunch with coworkers and I realized that sticking to a no-carb diet wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be so easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to switch out rice for lettuce in my burrito bowls, opt for salad where there was no substitutable option. (I hate lettuce, but oh well.) This was my first real encounter with having to pay attention to how much &amp;ldquo;filler&amp;rdquo; stuff we eat. When you take the rice out of a burrito, for example, it&amp;rsquo;s just a weird looking lump of things awkwardly wrapped inside of a deflating tortilla. (This is just an example, tortillas were forbidden.) Similarly, take any sandwich you can think of and remove the bread. All you&amp;rsquo;re left with is a slice of meat/chicken with some kind of sauce drizzled over it and a bunch of spinach leaves and onions on top. Sounds pretty lame? Yup. The bread makes up at least half the calories of the sandwich. Same situation with any kind of hoagie/cheesesteak/wrap style food. Sushi has rice around it, so do most Indian meals (or at least some kind of bread). Ramen has noodles. Italian is pretty much out the door, unless you only eat meatballs. Same case with most American versions of Mexican and creole food. It took a LOT of creativity and restrictions to be able to buy/makes lunches that had zero carbs. And pair all that with a guy who absolutely could not care less about salads and you have a real situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the struggles, I was able to manage through the week with only once breaking the rule. For Wedneday lunch I caved for a sandwich because I was simply too exhausted of having to explain to the server why I wanted to substitute bread for lettuce wraps. The first few days I was generally hungry even after a meal. I was eating significantly fewer calories, even though I was eating more throughout the day. Still, what I noticed was a significant improvement in general energy levels throughout the day. I suspect this was because carbs tend to exaggerate the afternoon food coma post a heavy lunch. So cutting that out helped quite a bit. It did often get kind of frustrating trying to come up with meals that didn&amp;rsquo;t just default to some kind of grains/noodles. I think this is one of the fundamental reasons why people end up just reducing the carb intake instead of letting it go completely. Also maybe because carbs are just simply delicious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s practical to cut out carbs completely, but I did have a consistent higher energy level throughout the week. Because I also cut out sugar for the week I noticed that my body wasn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;crashing&amp;rdquo; from sugar-highs anymore. I could be back from a full day of work and still be productive till midnight or so. I also think it&amp;rsquo;s one of the most effective ways to lose weight since you&amp;rsquo;re eating fewer calories with every meal. Cutting out just one aspect of a diet as opposed to overhauling it completely is also easier to stick to. I was pretty conscious about this though - I wasn&amp;rsquo;t trying to lose weight so I made sure I ate more small meals through the day to account for the cut in calorie count. That said, I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth it at least once or twice a year to try this and see how your body reacts. I&amp;rsquo;m by no means cutting out carbs completely but I think I&amp;rsquo;ve realized I need to decrease their amount in my diet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/fmanjoo/status/687755569311035392&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/fmanjoo/status/687755569311035392&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Couple of pointers and things that I noticed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was focusing only on eradicating complex-sugar carbs and food products where carbs are the primary ingredient (grains, for example). No specific reason, it&amp;rsquo;s just easier to do. Even Kale has carbs, but it&amp;rsquo;s not the majority/primary ingredient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first two or three days generally take getting used to since your body is expecting more food than you&amp;rsquo;re giving it. You might have a minor headache.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you stick to your general meal count, you end up eating fewer calories than you normally would. This is because most of the calorie intake happens through high-carb foods like breads, pasta, tortillas, rice, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; eat a lot more throughout the day as opposed to two or three big meals since all your meals are now smaller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almost everything I read mentioned the person losing weight when this was followed for longer periods of time. I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice any weight change in one week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt a lot less tired. This is the single-most vivid and biggest change I noticed. Because the amount of calories going in at once decreased I felt that the general tendency of a minor afternoon workplace food-coma also dramatically decreased. I actually went through a whole day feeling active and energetic throughout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintaining a zero carb diet can get expensive - you have no &amp;ldquo;filler&amp;rdquo; foods so your general entrée consumption increases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning a City Again</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/learning-a-city-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/learning-a-city-again/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids=&amp;ldquo;1127,1128,1129&amp;rdquo; type=&amp;ldquo;slideshow&amp;rdquo; link=&amp;ldquo;file&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was last in Delhi (a little over 2 years ago) I was walking around in the Ballimaran area of Delhi-6. It is chaotic, smelly, extremely overcrowded, and full of delicious food. I was with my cousin and we had overlapping but tangential agendas. Both of us were driven by wanting to get some authentic Delhi-6 street food. I also wanted to explore some old booksellers in Ballimaran and he had to get his glasses made &amp;ndash; which, in that area, is done pretty cheaply and with good enough quality. After having made our way through the many parathas and &lt;em&gt;dahi balle&lt;/em&gt; and the countless kulfis and jalebis, we finally went back to pick up his glasses. The sun was setting and we were there at an opportune time - it was Ramadan and people were about to break their fast. Ballimaran is close to Jama Masjid and so the &lt;em&gt;iftar&lt;/em&gt; preparations there were in full-throttle mode. After a while of retracing our steps to the glasses store (it is easy to get lost there even as a seasoned veteran of those lanes) and narrowly avoiding rickshaws rocketing by, the sun was finally down, the streets were lit up, and people everywhere were offering anyone a seat to join them in breaking their fast together. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that if I would have just walked up to street vendors and asked for food they would have given it for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we got to the store, we were told by the owner that he had &amp;lsquo;upgraded&amp;rsquo; the lens in the glasses and put a &amp;lsquo;better&amp;rsquo; one on than the one he had promised, however it was going to cost us a little more. (This seems to happen a lot around here.) We refused, and he nudged a little further all the while bringing the &amp;rsquo;extra&amp;rsquo; cost down slowly until my cousin finally agreed to an amount, both parties only half-satisfied with the negotiations. The owner was talking to us this whole while but what I hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed was that when we had walked in he had left his meal midway (the Ramadan fast that he was also breaking) while the rest of his crew continued to eat. And then something interesting happened. After the passionate haggling the owner invited us to join them for food! We were stuffed but it also seemed rude to say no to such a generous offer, and he was more than enthusiastic about the offer, so it never felt like it was being done out formality. Besides, when was the last time a random shopkeeper invited you for a meal out of formality? And that too after having negotiated a price he didn&amp;rsquo;t seem satisfied with? We explained that while he was fixing the glasses we had been eating to our heart&amp;rsquo;s and stomach&amp;rsquo;s content. Eventually, he only let us off after we&amp;rsquo;d each had a &lt;em&gt;dhokla&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has become one of my favorite stories about Delhi-6 and Delhi in general, and now when I travel in the States, something I often think about en route is what it takes to really know a city. To truly understand a place, its people, and culture whether you&amp;rsquo;ve grown up there or just drove in from a thousand miles away. And over time I&amp;rsquo;ve slowly kind of wandered my way into some kind of an answer for it - to know a city one ought to know its markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t believe you can truly know a place without first having immersed yourself in what I call its &lt;em&gt;grunge.&lt;/em&gt; There&amp;rsquo;s a reason Delhi-6 and its surroundings are attractive - they&amp;rsquo;re the grunge of the city. Not necessarily the &amp;lsquo;dirty&amp;rsquo; but more so the rustic &amp;ndash; the vintage that managed to exist through time. The gritty bylanes where the energy of today meets the resilience of history, where traditions collide and coalesce into something beautiful that lies precariously between a sense of nostalgia and wonder. Where even someone who&amp;rsquo;s grown up in Delhi can walk in and feel momentarily transformed by the air. I have come to believe that it is only after having first witnessed the overwhelming sights, sounds, and smells of a local market of any place do you get to know what it&amp;rsquo;s all about. The beat of the street, the way the people interact, the rhythm of activity that may appear chaotic initially but often has a definite process all end up making the city. And often they&amp;rsquo;re what the city is really about. It&amp;rsquo;s no wonder that the &lt;em&gt;bazaars&lt;/em&gt; of Istanbul are famous tourist attractions. As Delhi-6 does for Delhi, the bazaars offer a different personality of the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To every city (I use the term &amp;lsquo;city&amp;rsquo; very loosely here but it can be any place) there are at least two sides, if not more. There is the side facing the exterior, the world per se - the tourist pull to the place. Then there is the side that is the city on a daily basis - the daily grind, the hustle, all the things that make up the mundane existence of life there - the city equivalent of the time-space gap between great events in history where seemingly nothing happens. But just as these time gaps in great events are really the catalysts to the great events, these seemingly mundane qualities of a city that contribute to its daily bustle are the hidden gems of visiting any new place for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I left Ballimaran late that evening after gorging on some biryani for dinner, I realized how little I had really known Delhi despite having lived there for most of my life. What I did find in those bustling streets in the company of good food and good people was that it was never too late to get to know a place again. That remains to this day one of my favorite memories from that summer in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chandni Chowk streets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.indianholiday.com/photo-gallery/delhi-gallery/delhi-tourist-attractions/markets-in-delhi/chandni-chowk/Chandni-Chowk-2-500.jpg&#34;&gt;http://www.indianholiday.com/photo-gallery/delhi-gallery/delhi-tourist-attractions/markets-in-delhi/chandni-chowk/Chandni-Chowk-2-500.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chandni Chowk food&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.new-delhi-hotels.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Chandni-Chowk-Food.jpg&#34;&gt;http://www.new-delhi-hotels.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Chandni-Chowk-Food.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nai Sarak books&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ixigo-com-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t&#34;&gt;https://ixigo-com-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t&lt;/a&gt;_large,f_auto/nai-sarak-images-photos-51cd2a7046054ad777000001.jpg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>