<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>exit-series on Ayushman Khazanchi</title>
    <link>https://akzn.me/tags/exit-series/</link>
    <description>Recent content in exit-series on Ayushman Khazanchi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akzn.me/tags/exit-series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exit Series - Ethos</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/exit-series-ethos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/exit-series-ethos/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Write small, they say. These fancy sentences will take you nowhere but down. These are the king’s domain and don’t you know, all kings get their heads cut off? You don’t know the times, they say, don’t know the culture. They say, history is written by the collective crowd for it is the loudest. Sway your steps to its rhythm. Slow the pace of your fat pen that knows only to criticize. Arrest your hands from lecherous abandon for what else is it that you write? Lock your rooms of voice and reason well for you may never be allowed to step in again. Speak to no one unless it’s by the collective scripture. History is in the making and remaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summon the strength to listen for it is your only freedom. Listen as if your life depended on it. Listen to record, to preserve, to keep books. Be the accountant to history. Be the ear to the obnoxious beating drum of authority. Keep your artistic license in close and do not reveal it. Do not revel in it either. Your culture persists but you are new again. Carry the weight of balance in your delicate hands and when the time comes pass it on to the rightful heir. You will know one when they arrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are people born to bear burden. Speak of them highly for they carry your voice, your words, your art, silent and distant, like the sound of rocks ricocheting off a precipice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is part of &lt;a href=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/category/exit-series/&#34;&gt;Exit Series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exit Series - Spaces</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/exit-series-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/exit-series-spaces/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am thinking of the spaces we occupy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Places like this where I’m sitting amidst palm trees, a clear blue swimming pool, wicker chairs, some lemon water. A small lapse in perception and one could be fooled into thinking one were somewhere exotic. Like Sri Lanka. Or the Maldives. Yet these are only the calamitous ruins of a corporate city dense with dust and populace. A city constantly moving past even its own history. How effortlessly they change its name from Gurgaon to Gurugram, wiping its slate clean. Yet nothing gives here, not even its people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am thinking of the spaces I occupy —&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;these places in the mind that serve as escapes. An oasis of respite from the sometimes incomprehensible moorings of daily life. These are not wiped clean by the schemings of any mind. These are where things begin. Most days I move freely in these rooms, bartering questions with a false sense of longing and belonging:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am here and yet is there an elsewhere too where things begin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is part of &lt;a href=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/category/exit-series/&#34;&gt;Exit Series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exit Series - Cultural Criticism</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/exit-series-cultural-criticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/exit-series-cultural-criticism/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One Saturday I find myself walking these streets that I have known intimately for almost 3 years now. 17th street leading to Locust leading to 18th to Sansom and eventually to Joseph Fox Books which is where I&amp;rsquo;m headed right now. This is a pretty elongated route to get to the bookstore from my place (I could cut at least 3 blocks). I prefer this way though, because it takes you by the edge of Rittenhouse park and &lt;em&gt;Parc&lt;/em&gt;, a lively French restaurant. I am not looking for anything in particular and I&amp;rsquo;m certainly averse to spending money on another book, but I like browsing the shelves and the desire to not be alone at home on this Saturday morning has propelled me here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the bookstore, I am listening in on a conversation between the staff and a prospective customer. They&amp;rsquo;re looking up Hilton Als&amp;rsquo; White Girls to understand what it&amp;rsquo;s about - the girl had inquired about it. &amp;ldquo;Cultural criticism&amp;rdquo; is what a cursory search on the internet brings up and the customer, probably looking for a summer beach-read and entirely dissuaded by the weight of the result, promptly shelves the book. I haven&amp;rsquo;t read it but know that &amp;ldquo;cultural criticism&amp;rdquo; barely does justice to the book. I wonder how Hilton Als feels about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I browse through some books on design and art &amp;ndash; genres I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in lately &amp;ndash; but since I didn&amp;rsquo;t come here to buy anything I end up leaving soon after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is part of &lt;a href=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/category/exit-series/&#34;&gt;Exit Series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exit Series Surprise</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/exit-series-surprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/exit-series-surprise/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Outside, a thunderstorm has slowly gained momentum and I, unbeknownst to its advances, step out of a bookstore realizing I am not carrying an umbrella. I have been walking the city, examining and observing it. A few blocks down from the bookstore C and I get caught in the storm and I, having a laptop in my bag, run the rest of the way home. I am soaked anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dried and changed I watch the rest of the storm sitting by my window with a hot cup of tea. Of course I&amp;rsquo;m also working on the side. It is from here I witness something I have only seen a handful of times in my life. It is something I always find a little odd, but somehow also peaceful. Outside the rain is pouring steadily downwards. No wind disturbs the flow to create sheets of water. (This happens a lot in Delhi.) However, what&amp;rsquo;s odd and surprising is that there are no clouds and the sun shines undisturbed. I have rarely ever seen it rain like this with clear skies and the sun out while it&amp;rsquo;s raining. When it rains in Delhi, and also when it rains here in Pennsylvania, the sky is almost always some shade of overcast or grey or dark and cloudy. The sun may or may not come out after the rain clouds have dispersed. But pouring rain without any clouds? It seems to me to be extremely rare but to notice it when it happens is a beautiful sight. A welcome surprise on an otherwise wet day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/category/exit-series/&#34;&gt;Exit Series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>