<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>community on Ayushman Khazanchi</title>
    <link>https://akzn.me/tags/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in community on Ayushman Khazanchi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akzn.me/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2016 - Numbers and Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/2016-numbers-and-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/2016-numbers-and-thoughts/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Overall 2016 was a good year for me. Here&amp;rsquo;s some thoughts on stuff that happened and what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from all of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was by far the most demanding year I&amp;rsquo;ve had at work. I started the year off with accepting more responsibility (I was made the Team Lead for one our internal products) and that has turned out to be one of the most interesting learning experiences this year. This gave me an interesting glimpse into the organizational side of things and kind of forced me to start looking at the bigger picture of where our team was going. It also helped me improve some of my non-technical, organizational, skills like estimates, scope, and time management. More than anything it forced me to prioritize what I wanted to/had to devote my time towards, especially when it came to communication. Email still sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The negative effects of context-switching are something that are often talked about in the developer world. What is it? It&amp;rsquo;s when you&amp;rsquo;re working on one thing and are required to immediately put it aside and work on something else entirely, thereby interrupting the flow you were in. It might be a meeting that&amp;rsquo;s scheduled or it might be your boss asking you to deliver something else first. It happens, and until we get to a point where no manager ever requests you to immediately switch contexts and you never get scheduled for a random middle-of-the-day meeting ever, we&amp;rsquo;re just going to have to get better at it. Taking on more work has put me in a situation where more people need stuff from me. So I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself having to switch focus a lot this year. I&amp;rsquo;m still not great at it but something I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that helps is to make a short list of &amp;lsquo;pending/next items&amp;rsquo; on the task that you&amp;rsquo;re working on before you put it aside. This has helped me get into it faster when I do return to it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the code I wrote this year has been for work but I did start getting into Android near the end of the year so more to follow on that in the coming months. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to have more time this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Play&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I&amp;rsquo;m really happy about is that I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing a lot of football (soccer) again. I found a group that plays pickup on weekend mornings and I try to go most games. I found this group pretty late in the year (around August) and ended up playing in one of the leagues they had going from September to November. I also played my first sub-zero temperature game so that was fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve volunteered a lot more this year, especially teaching kids coding once a week. What I&amp;rsquo;ve learned is this: being a good teacher, with the right balance of strictness &amp;amp; fun, is really hard. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how quickly you realize this when you start teaching kids. I have a newfound respect for teachers. I&amp;rsquo;m a little unnerved by the amount of access really young kids have to screens but also amazed at how fast they learn how to use tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I&amp;rsquo;ve had some interesting interactions with people on really hard and touchy subjects – politics, race, privacy, the role of media vs. citizens etc. Most of these interactions happened in person and the general sentiment has been that the digital platforms we&amp;rsquo;ve built are no longer the grounds for intellectual discussion that we&amp;rsquo;d hoped they&amp;rsquo;d become. I still believe that they can be, but it is up to us to put forth the kind of discussions we want to have. Whether we simply propagate our beliefs or we actually seek to understand is something in our control and no amount of blaming an ecosystem is going to really change that. This is something I get more skeptical about everyday but there is still hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put traveling on a hiatus near the end of the year. I got a little disillusioned and tired of it and I want to take some time to understand what I want out of it before I start again. I&amp;rsquo;ve talked to a lot of people about why they travel and the general answer is to experience new cultures but new cultures are also available within a block&amp;rsquo;s distance. And with the current political climate it may actually help to connect with the cultures in our communities. Despite all this I did manage to go to 15 cities, mostly to see friends and families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Fun Numbers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mostly calculated all these off of memory - save for the books which Goodreads tracked &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/user/year_in_books/2016/5335295&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This has got me wondering if there&amp;rsquo;s an app to easily keep track of this&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table style=&#34;height: 246px;&#34; width=&#34;606&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Books I read this year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Poems I added to a poetry collaboration &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/christutolo&#34;&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; and I started last year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Poems we added in total this year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;33&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;People I learned something from or had a good time with (caveat: only people I met in person this year and spent at least a few hours with)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Cities/places I visited&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Podcast finished (How I Built This, NPR)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;football matches played&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;7&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;1623,1661,1663,1666,1669,1670,1672&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can You Imagine?</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/can-you-imagine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 14:10:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/can-you-imagine/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1049&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;250&amp;rdquo;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/kalman_principlesofuncertainty2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/kalman_principlesofuncertainty2.png?w=194&#34; alt=&#34;Image of a page from Maira Kalman&amp;amp;rsquo;s The Principles of Uncertainty&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Maira Kalman - The Principles of Uncertainty[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you imagine being so alone, so helpless that you&amp;rsquo;re stuck in the middle-divider of a busy road on an electric wheelchair with your batteries bust? I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even picture something like this happening until I saw it happen to someone today. It rattled me a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the time of our lives that we spend on growing and building our community and then we go out alone. On my way back from work I cross a four lane road that, around office rush-hour time, is bumper to bumper traffic. Bad enough that cars frequently spill into the box trying to make it past the traffic lights. There&amp;rsquo;s only about ten seconds of a walk signal on this crossing. It&amp;rsquo;s not bad, can be done easily enough even if all you&amp;rsquo;ve got are jello-legs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, though, while walking up to the intersection, I saw an old man on one of those electric wheelchairs stuck in the middle of the road fiddling with the controls on the right handle. Initially I just glanced at him and didn&amp;rsquo;t pay much heed (the limits of our attention, right?). It really only struck me that there was even a problem when I was already halfway through crossing the road and the guy still hadn&amp;rsquo;t moved, was still fiddling with the controls. (There&amp;rsquo;s a fairly decent-sized divider in the middle of the road so he wasn&amp;rsquo;t literally on the road or in danger.) Since I was crossing from the other side, I decided I&amp;rsquo;d cross back and help him out (that darned ten second timer) but when I got to his side there was already a student who, having crossed up to the same point as the old man and mid-way having noticed his immobility, asked him if there was a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1048&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;265&amp;rdquo;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/kalman11.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/kalman11.png?w=226&#34; alt=&#34;Image of a page from Maira Kalman&amp;amp;rsquo;s The Principles of Uncertainty&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Maira Kalman - The Principles of Uncertainty[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course there was. I watched from the other end &amp;ndash; though I couldn&amp;rsquo;t hear them over the traffic &amp;ndash; and I saw the old man, obviously feeling embarrassed, denying the offer of help as if it was just a simple thing he could brush off any minute. Like someone just made a mistake and soon things would be fine. Like the wheelchair was just playing games on him. Not a problem. But we drop all our walls when we honestly need, and want, genuine help. I&amp;rsquo;m glad the guy stuck around despite the old man initially declining his offer. He wheeled him over in the next ten second interval as I stood on the other side, the angst-ridden equivalent of helpless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other side, safer and what seemed to be a little bit relaxed, the man continued to fiddle with his controls, not acknowledging our presence. We didn&amp;rsquo;t mind. Life is hard enough. We stood around for a while unsure as to the extent of our responsibility. I asked eventually if we could call him a cab, but he refused. The student asked him if he could call someone who could pick him up. He refused. We looked at each other. Was there even someone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I eventually asked if it would work, foolishly hoping for some kind of emergency-battery mechanism or something to prevent exactly these situations. Now searching through the cords for something under the seat, he said it would. Confident, short answers. After a few minutes and a few remarks from the old man that he was fine, and obviously otherwise being of very little help, we decided to leave. What can you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked away a little heartbroken, a little disappointed that for all the money and all our information and all the apps and all the people around on the busiest street in town, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t get a man home, couldn&amp;rsquo;t get him to safely cross the road with dignity and without fear - without that thought that will now remain etched in his mind as he whizzes around - that someday his wheelchair might run out of juice, a wheel might get caught in a pothole (happened as he was pushed across road) or it might just flat-out breakdown. Or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s happened before. How else was he so sure it would work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I turned around after a few steps to check if he was still there but he wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>