<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hilton-als on Ayushman Khazanchi</title>
    <link>https://akzn.me/tags/hilton-als/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hilton-als on Ayushman Khazanchi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akzn.me/tags/hilton-als/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exit Series - Cultural Criticism</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/exit-series-cultural-criticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/exit-series-cultural-criticism/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One Saturday I find myself walking these streets that I have known intimately for almost 3 years now. 17th street leading to Locust leading to 18th to Sansom and eventually to Joseph Fox Books which is where I&amp;rsquo;m headed right now. This is a pretty elongated route to get to the bookstore from my place (I could cut at least 3 blocks). I prefer this way though, because it takes you by the edge of Rittenhouse park and &lt;em&gt;Parc&lt;/em&gt;, a lively French restaurant. I am not looking for anything in particular and I&amp;rsquo;m certainly averse to spending money on another book, but I like browsing the shelves and the desire to not be alone at home on this Saturday morning has propelled me here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the bookstore, I am listening in on a conversation between the staff and a prospective customer. They&amp;rsquo;re looking up Hilton Als&amp;rsquo; White Girls to understand what it&amp;rsquo;s about - the girl had inquired about it. &amp;ldquo;Cultural criticism&amp;rdquo; is what a cursory search on the internet brings up and the customer, probably looking for a summer beach-read and entirely dissuaded by the weight of the result, promptly shelves the book. I haven&amp;rsquo;t read it but know that &amp;ldquo;cultural criticism&amp;rdquo; barely does justice to the book. I wonder how Hilton Als feels about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I browse through some books on design and art &amp;ndash; genres I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in lately &amp;ndash; but since I didn&amp;rsquo;t come here to buy anything I end up leaving soon after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is part of &lt;a href=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/category/exit-series/&#34;&gt;Exit Series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>