<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>work on Ayushman Khazanchi</title>
    <link>https://akzn.me/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in work on Ayushman Khazanchi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 01:16:08 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akzn.me/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Code</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 01:16:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/code/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an unorganized list of some (non-work) code + fun stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve done in my free time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tiny-aes&#34;&gt;Tiny AES&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Python)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tiny implementation of AES ECB encryption in Python. &lt;a href=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/tiny-aes-in-python&#34;&gt;Read more about it here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;distributed-intelligent-agents&#34;&gt;Distributed Intelligent Agents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Gama Programming Language)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various different GAMA prototypesbuilt around concepts of distributed agent communication, negotiation, auctions, and resolution based on the GAML simulation language. Picked up the basics of this language within a few days which is quite a feat in itself considering the absolute lack of good documentation around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;eventy&#34;&gt;Eventy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Python, Flask, SQLite)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rapid prototype app that I developed for the ID2207 - Modern Methods of Software Engineering course. The app was an event planner app that depicted certain user and data control flows based around a brief for a Swedish event planning company provided to us during the course. The prototype has functionality for ticket creation and having it pass through the various stages of approval/rejection by each concerned department until completion of the workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;distributed-systems&#34;&gt;Distributed Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Erlang)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some simple prototypes written in Erlang as part of our Distributed Systems course at KTH:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rudy: simple web server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Routy: small routing protocol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loggy: logical time logger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groupy: group membership service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chordy: distributed hash table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;send-pups-bot&#34;&gt;Send Pups Bot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Python, Flask, Twilio API)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a chatbot that sends you photos of cute pups on Whatsapp. It has a basic Flask backend and uses Twilio&amp;rsquo;s Whatsapp API. It uses the free Sandbox trial by Twilio and is deployed on Heroku so it may take some time to respond the first time as it wakes up. More about it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;100citiesfrommemory&#34;&gt;#100CitiesFromMemory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve long wanted to a do #100DaysProject. At the end of March 2020, I was convinced by a friend to start one. I started a writing project that imagined a city from memory as a response to a picture I had taken. I only got to 62 cities 😔 before it got a bit overwhelming during the Coronavirus-cum-lockdown-cum-pandemic situation. I will return to this soon, though. You can go through the project here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;philly-skyline-bot&#34;&gt;Philly Skyline Bot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Python, Raspberry Pi)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometime back in 2017 I used a spare raspberry pi to take photos of the Philly Skyline from my then apartment window. The bot used to take a photo daily at 8 am and 8 pm with the raspberry pi camera module and then tweet the photos to the Twitter account. I think it was going for a month or two until I had to eventually change apartments. I made a timelapse of the skyline (with music and everything!) here and the now-defunct Twitter account is here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;coded-by-kids-philadelphia&#34;&gt;Coded By Kids, Philadelphia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Philly I used to volunteer with this super organization (until Aug 2017) that teaches kids how to code (but also general digital literacy) which I think is a super important skill to have going forward. Check out Coded By Kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Year, So Far</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190317_095512-1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;Garhwal Mountains&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mid-year retrospective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being the middle of the year it felt like a good time to do a general retrospective on the year so far. The last few months have felt like I&amp;rsquo;m riding a sine wave and I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to figure out a general direction for some things. I wanted to pause and take stock of the year so far. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea when you feel overwhelmed to simply take a step back to catch a breath or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a new project at work which involved me visiting Melbourne for a few weeks. The work is challenging in that there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of room for growth and learning new tools and processes and Melbourne was a really fun city to experience. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get disillusioned by work but I try to remember that there are people that value my work and trust me enough to want to spend all this money on me to send me places on my own to figure stuff out unsupervised! Pretty wild, to be honest. It&amp;rsquo;s good to be reminded every once in a while that your professional responsibility occasionally extends beyond just your own immediate interests. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m back in India, the work continues from here and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to learn as much as possible while on this new project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190505_142557-1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;Yarra River with MCG to the Left&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;    
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190511_132941.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;Fitzroy&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;    
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190511_195045_605.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;View from the Room&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;    
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190512_142837.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;Bar Tini&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;    
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190518_143648_009.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;State Library of Victoria&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;    
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190518_182959_689.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;Performer, Bourke Street&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;    
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190519_133312_123.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;Flint Street Station&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;    
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190519_143855_353.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;St Kilda&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;    
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190519_172123.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;St Kilda&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;    
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190525_122015_892.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;Skyline from South Melbourne&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the time in Melbourne when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t working (evenings and weekends) I went around eating and drinking and exploring the city. Melbourne is full of art (both street art and museums) and is considered the cultural capital of Australia. It&amp;rsquo;s also a city full of immigrants and massively serious about their coffee and their espresso martinis. The Australian work culture is interesting. For someone who has worked in the US and in India, there is a lot of serious emphasis here on work-life balance and working towards increasing the general quality of life. The US likes to talk about it, India doesn&amp;rsquo;t even talk about it, but Australia (or Melbourne, at least) really seems to follow it. I even had someone tell me the people they were managing had actively rejected promotions and pay-raises so as not to disturb their equilibrium. The biggest thing is that it&amp;rsquo;s not really frowned upon. This is really new for someone coming from the Indian and American context. Oh and everything is super expensive in general because obviously they have a really good healthcare industry and the service industry is well paid. Tipping is not really a practice there, although I did find it prevalent in the touristy parts of the city. All in all, I had some preconceived ideas about Australia that I&amp;rsquo;ve since had to correct and some that were accurate were strengthened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;play&#34;&gt;Play&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been a half-year of somewhat surreal experiences. In January, I went down with some friends to Ranthambore National Park over a weekend to see some tigers. We booked as many safaris as we could cover in the weekend (3) while also leaving some time to experience Rajasthani food (mainly Raj Kachori) in the city. We were expecting to see &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; tigers, &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; laying around or deep in the jungle somewhere. We were absolutely not expecting to see tigers from up to two or three feet away. We were not expecting to see a tiger stare right at us, drinking water (those muscles!), marking her territory, and casually strolling behind us. It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly lucky to spot a tiger, even less to have it walk with you. You&amp;rsquo;re left in awe of the sheer power and grace they exude. We were too lucky and I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll ever experience something like this again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/2019-01-21-11.24.06-1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/2019-01-21-11.24.07-1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/2019-01-21-11.24.11-1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/2019-01-22-12.59.58-1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190122_132533_276.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190122_132533_279.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March I climbed the Nag Tibba summit with two friends. The summit is in the Garhwal region of Uttarakhand and is part of the lower Himalayan range. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the best weekend treks from Delhi and climbs up to a little over 3k meters (~9,900 ft.). It&amp;rsquo;s actually known to be a winter trek but we went at the tail-end of the winter season. Nearer to the summit on the last 2 km stretch we ran into almost knee-deep snow at some places but it was mostly clear up until then. It was an amazing experience and I&amp;rsquo;m already planning my next trek to Bhrigu Lake for the end of this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190317_101933.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;Overlooking Nanda Devi Range&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;    
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190316_123059.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;Garhwal Mountain&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;    
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190316_130223.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;Man on a Mission&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;    
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190316_162640_Bokeh.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;Base Camp&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;    
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190317_080837.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190317_095512.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;View from Summit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;    
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190317_102027_579.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190317_122634.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190317_173651_980.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/the-year-so-far/images/IMG_20190317_094937.jpg&#34; width=&#34;900&#34; height=&#34;800&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-family: &#39;PT Sans Narrow&#39;; font-weight:700&#34;&gt;Made it!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;service&#34;&gt;Service&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Near the end of Feb my dog, Fluffy, was diagnosed with kidney failure. She passed peacefully on June 20th after a long and amazing fight. It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a life-changing experience where we&amp;rsquo;ve all scrambled to work through it together with our differing opinions and aching hearts. To say we&amp;rsquo;ve all grown would be putting it mildly. But it is comforting to think that even in her last days she was in good spirits and walking around the house for 2-3 hours a day almost daily. Gratitude and love have taken on new meanings and I&amp;rsquo;m grateful to some friends who helped through the process and would inquire about her regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her passing also kind of opened me up to &lt;a href=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/keeping-count/&#34;&gt;writing again&lt;/a&gt; but it also got me thinking about service again. Teju Cole mentioned in a recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://harvardmagazine.com/2019/05/commencement-teju-cole&#34;&gt;commencement speech&lt;/a&gt; the need to use our privilege in service of others. He says, &amp;ldquo;&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip; expertise is not the destination,&amp;rsquo; he cautioned. &amp;lsquo;The destination is freedom. What can we do to free others? Sure, we are experts, but under what ethical pressures does this function? In other words, how do we become a door for others to pass through?&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; I like this idea of working towards freedom. Naval Ravikant also echoes this sentiment on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/naval-ravikant/&#34;&gt;Knowledge Project podcast&lt;/a&gt; in a way in saying that as he&amp;rsquo;s grown older he wants &lt;em&gt;freedom from&lt;/em&gt; things instead of &lt;em&gt;freedom to&lt;/em&gt; do things. I hope to do more in the line of service this year - either by giving my time or my resources towards things I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, I&amp;rsquo;m just grateful that where this year has taken, it has also given. Sometimes you lose someone you love and it feels, momentarily, like the world is a bit darker and you&amp;rsquo;ve lost a companion. But there is also gratitude for the moments you did get to spend together. I think of all the surreal experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve had this year and wonder if anything can top the feeling of climbing a mountain, or having a tiger mere feet away from you in all her grace and power, or the feeling of being given responsibility as the true validation that your work does matter and that your opinions do hold weight. It&amp;rsquo;s been a rather eventful and bittersweet half of the year. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping for more and more depth in the second half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 - Numbers and Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/2016-numbers-and-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/2016-numbers-and-thoughts/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Overall 2016 was a good year for me. Here&amp;rsquo;s some thoughts on stuff that happened and what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from all of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was by far the most demanding year I&amp;rsquo;ve had at work. I started the year off with accepting more responsibility (I was made the Team Lead for one our internal products) and that has turned out to be one of the most interesting learning experiences this year. This gave me an interesting glimpse into the organizational side of things and kind of forced me to start looking at the bigger picture of where our team was going. It also helped me improve some of my non-technical, organizational, skills like estimates, scope, and time management. More than anything it forced me to prioritize what I wanted to/had to devote my time towards, especially when it came to communication. Email still sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The negative effects of context-switching are something that are often talked about in the developer world. What is it? It&amp;rsquo;s when you&amp;rsquo;re working on one thing and are required to immediately put it aside and work on something else entirely, thereby interrupting the flow you were in. It might be a meeting that&amp;rsquo;s scheduled or it might be your boss asking you to deliver something else first. It happens, and until we get to a point where no manager ever requests you to immediately switch contexts and you never get scheduled for a random middle-of-the-day meeting ever, we&amp;rsquo;re just going to have to get better at it. Taking on more work has put me in a situation where more people need stuff from me. So I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself having to switch focus a lot this year. I&amp;rsquo;m still not great at it but something I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that helps is to make a short list of &amp;lsquo;pending/next items&amp;rsquo; on the task that you&amp;rsquo;re working on before you put it aside. This has helped me get into it faster when I do return to it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the code I wrote this year has been for work but I did start getting into Android near the end of the year so more to follow on that in the coming months. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to have more time this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Play&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I&amp;rsquo;m really happy about is that I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing a lot of football (soccer) again. I found a group that plays pickup on weekend mornings and I try to go most games. I found this group pretty late in the year (around August) and ended up playing in one of the leagues they had going from September to November. I also played my first sub-zero temperature game so that was fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve volunteered a lot more this year, especially teaching kids coding once a week. What I&amp;rsquo;ve learned is this: being a good teacher, with the right balance of strictness &amp;amp; fun, is really hard. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how quickly you realize this when you start teaching kids. I have a newfound respect for teachers. I&amp;rsquo;m a little unnerved by the amount of access really young kids have to screens but also amazed at how fast they learn how to use tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I&amp;rsquo;ve had some interesting interactions with people on really hard and touchy subjects – politics, race, privacy, the role of media vs. citizens etc. Most of these interactions happened in person and the general sentiment has been that the digital platforms we&amp;rsquo;ve built are no longer the grounds for intellectual discussion that we&amp;rsquo;d hoped they&amp;rsquo;d become. I still believe that they can be, but it is up to us to put forth the kind of discussions we want to have. Whether we simply propagate our beliefs or we actually seek to understand is something in our control and no amount of blaming an ecosystem is going to really change that. This is something I get more skeptical about everyday but there is still hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put traveling on a hiatus near the end of the year. I got a little disillusioned and tired of it and I want to take some time to understand what I want out of it before I start again. I&amp;rsquo;ve talked to a lot of people about why they travel and the general answer is to experience new cultures but new cultures are also available within a block&amp;rsquo;s distance. And with the current political climate it may actually help to connect with the cultures in our communities. Despite all this I did manage to go to 15 cities, mostly to see friends and families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Fun Numbers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mostly calculated all these off of memory - save for the books which Goodreads tracked &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/user/year_in_books/2016/5335295&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This has got me wondering if there&amp;rsquo;s an app to easily keep track of this&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table style=&#34;height: 246px;&#34; width=&#34;606&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Books I read this year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Poems I added to a poetry collaboration &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/christutolo&#34;&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; and I started last year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Poems we added in total this year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;33&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;People I learned something from or had a good time with (caveat: only people I met in person this year and spent at least a few hours with)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Cities/places I visited&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Podcast finished (How I Built This, NPR)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;football matches played&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;7&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;1623,1661,1663,1666,1669,1670,1672&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>