<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>world on Ayushman Khazanchi</title>
    <link>https://akzn.me/tags/world/</link>
    <description>Recent content in world on Ayushman Khazanchi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akzn.me/tags/world/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Count</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/keeping-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/keeping-count/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/IMG_20190621_224218_737-3-819x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Clouds over Heritage City, June 21&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heritage City, June 21&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been in a gigantic creative block for a long time. Pretty sure I&amp;rsquo;m in the writing dungeons by now. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I even remember the last time I wrote something longer than 250 words that wasn&amp;rsquo;t either an email, documentation on code, or something required for work. Recently though something happened that got me into it again. For the last week or so I&amp;rsquo;ve waded into the waters privately to see how cold and frigid my skills have become. They&amp;rsquo;re rusty, to put it mildly, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. At least not for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dog, Fluffy, passed away on June 20th after a long (and pretty amazing) fight against kidney failure. Early morning while I was sitting by her side observing her physical self for the last time ever it struck me that I needed to start writing again. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why &amp;ndash; my dog has never been my writing muse. In fact I&amp;rsquo;d even go so far as to say writing about my dog has been the hardest of all topics. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been able to write about her or what she meant to me or what she has taught me or anything really. Never could do it justice. But somehow in that moment as I was looking at her tired and frail form finally at peace after a long fight &amp;ndash; trying to iron it into my memory so I never forget her &amp;ndash; I kept thinking that to write again would be to honor her. After all, we are but stories eventually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think a lot about why I had this thought but I&amp;rsquo;ve not able to figure it out myself. I stopped writing because it didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense at the time. The world seemed to be falling apart and &lt;em&gt;having&lt;/em&gt; an opinion at the time seemed to matter more than being informed. So I took some time away to experience the world without feeling the need to record it. I like writing; I don&amp;rsquo;t have plans to become a full-time writer. I figured if the well had dried up on its own, it would also one day fill up again. It&amp;rsquo;s not filled up at all but somehow it feels right that the time is now. It feels like a way to keep count and keeping count matters in the times we live in now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also time now after a long break to try and understand the dissonance of the times we&amp;rsquo;re living in. Everyday there is something to be outraged about. Everyday there is a new disaster or impending doom or an unexplainable policy. Our virtual communities &amp;ndash; these networks we proclaimed as the social future &amp;ndash; are doing everything to further distance people. It&amp;rsquo;s commonplace enough now that even the preceding statement has become a tiresome bore. I watched in Philly in 2016 as Trump got elected, seemingly out of nowhere. I watched Modi get elected and then re-elected this year with a majority that was either a surprise or wasn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ndash; depending on which side you were on. I watch even today as politicians mired in disturbing criminal cases run the highest offices of the country. I watch as debates dissolve into endless shout-fests and the use of terms like &amp;ldquo;libtards&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sickular&amp;rdquo; are considered not only acceptable but pretty much the norm of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe a lot of the dissonance is simply due to the fact that we&amp;rsquo;re so deeply disconnected from the realities of the environment around us and only now are those fault lines coming to surface. As a result, I&amp;rsquo;ve become wary of people who seem to have all the answers and explanations to current events. I&amp;rsquo;m wary especially of those who seem confident and able to pinpoint entire systems down to one or two or three clever hot-takes. There are core truths, of course, but I don&amp;rsquo;t believe anymore that we&amp;rsquo;re capable of explaining, or even understanding, the social and civic issues splitting our collective fabric while we sit in our internet-connected armchairs far away from where the struggle plays out daily. This world feels too different for anyone to just &amp;ldquo;know&amp;rdquo; it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m reading more. Reflecting more. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to write again. I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking a lot of pictures this year. Recording, reflecting, revising. Channeling my effort in a different direction &amp;ndash; hopefully something more positive than just outrage and hot-takes and endless debates with people who have no skin in the game, so to speak. Trying, at least. This is an attempt to start to put my thoughts down as I try to figure them out. Minimal to no editing or refactoring or filtering on this. Just keeping count.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading - May 2018</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/reading-may-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/reading-may-2018/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Collections is an attempt at keeping a monthly record of the pieces of writing/art/media that I’ve found valuable and interesting. More about the series &lt;a href=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/category/collections/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stratechery.com/2018/the-bill-gates-line/&#34;&gt;// The Bill Gates Line&lt;/a&gt; (Tech)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Windows was indeed the ultimate platform — the company used to brag about only capturing a minority of the total value of the Windows ecosystem — and the operating system’s clear successors are Amazon Web Services and Microsoft’s own Azure Cloud Services. In all three cases there are strong and durable businesses to be built on top.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the difference between platforms and aggregators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.recode.net/2018/5/30/17385116/mary-meeker-slides-internet-trends-code-conference-2018&#34;&gt;// Mary Meeker&amp;rsquo;s 2018 Internet Trends Report&lt;/a&gt; (World / Tech)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High growth in mobile usage, easier payments, China&amp;rsquo;s inevitable tech dominance &amp;ndash; this is always a fun and insightful slide deck (attached at the end of the article).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mobile.nytimes.com/2018/05/24/magazine/what-does-it-mean-to-look-at-this.html&#34;&gt;// What Does It Mean to Look at This?&lt;/a&gt; (Art)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Photographs of atrocity always confront us with questions of inequality. But these questions can no longer simply be reduced to &amp;lsquo;Why them and why not us?&amp;rsquo; If, as Azoulay argues, photography deterritorializes citizenship, then these images accuse, they interrogate and they put us in the same boat with those we are looking at. &amp;lsquo;What have we done,&amp;rsquo; they ask us, &amp;rsquo;to create the conditions in which others, our fellow citizens, undergo these unspeakable experiences?&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading - April 2018</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/reading-april-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/reading-april-2018/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Collections&lt;/em&gt; is an attempt at keeping a monthly record of the pieces of writing/art/media that I&amp;rsquo;ve found valuable and interesting. More about the series &lt;a href=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/category/collections/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2018-quest-for-billion-dollar-red/&#34;&gt;// The Quest for the Next Billion Dollar Color&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(World)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;YInMn blue (pronounced YIN-min) is an amalgam of yttrium, indium oxide, and manganese—elements deep within the periodic table that together form something unique. YInMn was the first blue pigment discovered in more than 200 years&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world lacks a great all-around red. Always has. We’ve made do with alternatives that could be toxic or plain gross. The gladiators smeared their faces with mercury-based vermilion. Titian painted with an arsenic-based mineral called realgar. The British army’s red coats were infused with crushed cochineal beetles. For decades, red Lego bricks contained cadmium, a carcinogen.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really unexpected and interesting read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ncase.me/trust//&#34;&gt;// The Evolution of Trust&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Art / Tech)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ncase.me/&#34;&gt;Nicky Case&lt;/a&gt; makes some of my favorite interactive pieces on the web. The Evolution of Trust is an interactive game that explores various &amp;ldquo;approaches&amp;rdquo; to trust and cooperation. Beautifully explained, it ended up leaving me with more questions than answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thehindu.com/books/i-recognise-the-holiness-of-death-an-interview-with-amy-tan/article23398989.ece&#34;&gt;// I Recognise the Holiness of Death, an Interview with Amy Tan&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Social)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There’s the first breath, there’s the last breath, and everything that goes between. What we put in there as people and what we’ve left, what we’ve given. Not these pages in a library. This legacy. I think it’s false to count your symbolic immortality on published books. It has more to do with what you give to the world that lasts forever…&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This small interview has a lot of wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/04/16/the-silence-the-legacy-of-childhood-trauma&#34;&gt;// The Silence: The Legacy of Childhood Trauma&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Social)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not enough pages in the world to describe what it did to me. The whole planet could be my inkstand and it still wouldn’t be enough. That shit cracked the planet of me in half, threw me completely out of orbit, into the lightless regions of space where life is not possible.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Junot Diaz is in my top 3 favorite writers and the powerful force and beauty of his writing is visible in this unfortunate personal story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just a Little More Comfortable</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/just-a-little-more-comfortable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/just-a-little-more-comfortable/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While I was sitting during the commencement waiting for the proceedings to begin I remembered a statement made by one of my professors a few years ago. It was a motivator for us to consciously appreciate the environment we were in during his class and, roughly paraphrased, it was this: Never again, after having graduated from here, will you be able to replicate the environment you&amp;rsquo;re in today, where there are countless others like you, with similar ideas and ambitions, broad and open minds who want to effect changes in the world to make it just a little more comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the one moment when graduation suddenly felt real. You ever feel that it&amp;rsquo;s mostly among the optimists and the dreamers and the do-ers that we, too, feel creative and emboldened? That those who do and discuss larger-than-us ideas make us feel a little more alive? Fill us up a little with a sense of purpose?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be told that numerically such a concentration would be hard to find in the rest of your life is a depressing thought. Couple that with realizing that you&amp;rsquo;re 23 years old and among the oldest few in the room, and all your closest dorm room friends now have to take a flight and a train before they could even knock on your door is a realization too heavy for mid-commencement ceremonies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met that professor in my junior year when I took a class on social entrepreneurship that affirmed what I had long felt about myself. I knew then that I wanted to work in the social field somewhere in the long run. What I had lacked until then was the environment where there were others with similar desires and open minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right from the start the class was different. The projects mattered because they were real-world projects with real-world consequences and real-world people working on them full-time on some different continent in different countries, and what you did or didn&amp;rsquo;t do during the semester directly affected someone&amp;rsquo;s livelihood. And given that we were working on making our small share of the &amp;lsquo;dent&amp;rsquo; in reducing food wastage (specifically, in Africa), it directly affected someone&amp;rsquo;s survival too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was among the hardest classes I&amp;rsquo;ve taken, not for the number of hours it required but because it challenged us every step of the way to push ourselves beyond our limits. Up until then I had heard the phrase &amp;ldquo;out of the box thinking&amp;rdquo; being tossed around like a ping-pong ball to the extent that it was more likely I&amp;rsquo;d judge someone negatively simply for using that phrase. Semesters would start with professors regurgitating the same phrases, trying to make their classes sound more exciting and, in turn, end up sounding exactly the same. Cue the yawns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all that, there seemed a buzz in even the most boring classes. Moving on to a new phase of life, I already miss the environment. The late-night debates on world politics while eating cheez-its straight from the box or the unending conversations on how to make the world a better place, there was, in all, a common thread of ambition extending beyond just the self. That to work for something bigger than oneself was not just a good life, it was the essence. This is, for me, one of the reasons I enjoyed college quite a bit in my last two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize now that to be able to maintain such a desire requires constant revision of one&amp;rsquo;s own biases &amp;ndash; something one can fall prey to quite easily outside of the company of similar minds. (It&amp;rsquo;s no surprise that adults are by far the worst learners. The biases are at their peak.) It is far too easy to blame the &amp;lsquo;system&amp;rsquo; or lose hope in negativity or just sit back in comfort so as not to disrupt the state of things. I find it senseless and devoid of purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found people who were willing to discuss bigger things. I found them willing to take on mundane, menial tasks in order to nudge the system just a little. I found passion in people with inspiring and unnerving ambitions, but most importantly I saw that positively working on something, despite their being no fruitful outcome to it, led others to want to help you succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I think about this more and more, wondering what I can do to effect change in my own way now that I&amp;rsquo;ve left this electrifying atmosphere behind, I am reminded of a brilliant point made by the same professor: Let&amp;rsquo;s allow ourselves to rise above the talk and focus simply on making the world just a little more comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>