<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>learning on Ayushman Khazanchi</title>
    <link>https://akzn.me/tags/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in learning on Ayushman Khazanchi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akzn.me/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2016 - Numbers and Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/2016-numbers-and-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/2016-numbers-and-thoughts/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Overall 2016 was a good year for me. Here&amp;rsquo;s some thoughts on stuff that happened and what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from all of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was by far the most demanding year I&amp;rsquo;ve had at work. I started the year off with accepting more responsibility (I was made the Team Lead for one our internal products) and that has turned out to be one of the most interesting learning experiences this year. This gave me an interesting glimpse into the organizational side of things and kind of forced me to start looking at the bigger picture of where our team was going. It also helped me improve some of my non-technical, organizational, skills like estimates, scope, and time management. More than anything it forced me to prioritize what I wanted to/had to devote my time towards, especially when it came to communication. Email still sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The negative effects of context-switching are something that are often talked about in the developer world. What is it? It&amp;rsquo;s when you&amp;rsquo;re working on one thing and are required to immediately put it aside and work on something else entirely, thereby interrupting the flow you were in. It might be a meeting that&amp;rsquo;s scheduled or it might be your boss asking you to deliver something else first. It happens, and until we get to a point where no manager ever requests you to immediately switch contexts and you never get scheduled for a random middle-of-the-day meeting ever, we&amp;rsquo;re just going to have to get better at it. Taking on more work has put me in a situation where more people need stuff from me. So I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself having to switch focus a lot this year. I&amp;rsquo;m still not great at it but something I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that helps is to make a short list of &amp;lsquo;pending/next items&amp;rsquo; on the task that you&amp;rsquo;re working on before you put it aside. This has helped me get into it faster when I do return to it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the code I wrote this year has been for work but I did start getting into Android near the end of the year so more to follow on that in the coming months. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to have more time this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Play&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I&amp;rsquo;m really happy about is that I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing a lot of football (soccer) again. I found a group that plays pickup on weekend mornings and I try to go most games. I found this group pretty late in the year (around August) and ended up playing in one of the leagues they had going from September to November. I also played my first sub-zero temperature game so that was fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve volunteered a lot more this year, especially teaching kids coding once a week. What I&amp;rsquo;ve learned is this: being a good teacher, with the right balance of strictness &amp;amp; fun, is really hard. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how quickly you realize this when you start teaching kids. I have a newfound respect for teachers. I&amp;rsquo;m a little unnerved by the amount of access really young kids have to screens but also amazed at how fast they learn how to use tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I&amp;rsquo;ve had some interesting interactions with people on really hard and touchy subjects – politics, race, privacy, the role of media vs. citizens etc. Most of these interactions happened in person and the general sentiment has been that the digital platforms we&amp;rsquo;ve built are no longer the grounds for intellectual discussion that we&amp;rsquo;d hoped they&amp;rsquo;d become. I still believe that they can be, but it is up to us to put forth the kind of discussions we want to have. Whether we simply propagate our beliefs or we actually seek to understand is something in our control and no amount of blaming an ecosystem is going to really change that. This is something I get more skeptical about everyday but there is still hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put traveling on a hiatus near the end of the year. I got a little disillusioned and tired of it and I want to take some time to understand what I want out of it before I start again. I&amp;rsquo;ve talked to a lot of people about why they travel and the general answer is to experience new cultures but new cultures are also available within a block&amp;rsquo;s distance. And with the current political climate it may actually help to connect with the cultures in our communities. Despite all this I did manage to go to 15 cities, mostly to see friends and families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Fun Numbers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mostly calculated all these off of memory - save for the books which Goodreads tracked &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/user/year_in_books/2016/5335295&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This has got me wondering if there&amp;rsquo;s an app to easily keep track of this&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table style=&#34;height: 246px;&#34; width=&#34;606&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Books I read this year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Poems I added to a poetry collaboration &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/christutolo&#34;&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; and I started last year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Poems we added in total this year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;33&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;People I learned something from or had a good time with (caveat: only people I met in person this year and spent at least a few hours with)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Cities/places I visited&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Podcast finished (How I Built This, NPR)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;football matches played&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;7&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;1623,1661,1663,1666,1669,1670,1672&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Habits</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/building-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/building-habits/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For a while I&amp;rsquo;ve been really interested in learning about the best models for building and sticking to habits. Part of this is of course stimulated by my own desire to improve and change some of my habits. Over the last five or six years I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to build some habits into my routine to the point that they don&amp;rsquo;t require any effort anymore (reading daily) and miserably failed at some others (working out regularly).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of my series of learning something new every week (another habit I&amp;rsquo;m trying to build), I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about different models for cultivating better habits/routines. This can apply fairly broadly to anything one wants to implement into their daily routine but in my case it&amp;rsquo;s driven by wanting to be more productive with my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also used a lot of apps and productivity/habit tools and these, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to believe, are at best support systems and not something you can completely rely on. They&amp;rsquo;re nice to mark a checkbox at the end of the day or keep your &amp;ldquo;habit chain&amp;rdquo; from breaking but they&amp;rsquo;re not actually going to get you to the gym. That part is still on you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings me to a model I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about, particularly because I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself doing something similar naturally. I learned about this model while reading The Power of Habit by Charles Duhigg. It boils down essentially to this simple yet revealing diagram drawn by researchers at MIT -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;218&amp;rdquo;]&lt;img src=&#34;https://akzn.me/blog/building-habits/images/Habitloop.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; The Habit Loop[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 
Simply put, in order to change habits -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the routine first and foremost
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what you&amp;rsquo;re doing, what&amp;rsquo;s leading to it, what is the result, how you feel at the end, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a suitable reward for when you perform the right/new/better habit
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rewards are like drugs - nice and helpful drugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinpoint the triggers (cues) that lead to the old habit
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These are the instinctive moments/actions/ circumstances etc. that lead you into the old routine. Identify these but don&amp;rsquo;t fight them just yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make an alternative plan when those triggers take place
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The idea is not to remove the trigger but to replace the routine set off by that trigger with a new and better routine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image source: http://habitica.wikia.com/wiki/The_Habit_Loop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gap in Learning Code and Building With Code</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/the-gap-in-learning-code-and-building-with-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/the-gap-in-learning-code-and-building-with-code/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;tl;dr: A post about what I feel is missing from &amp;ldquo;learn to code&amp;rdquo; services - one reason why new coders get frustrated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a traditional CS degree. Most people I hang out with at work wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know that right off the bat. If you&amp;rsquo;re a programmer, people assume that you must have a CS degree. Though I did have programming classes in college, none of them were nearly as in-depth as one would expect to get out of a four year college education. (This was also the case for most classes, not just CS.) As a result, most of what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about programming has been self-taught through building things and taking help from peers and a lot of online resources. The software industry in general is one of the only industries today where everything you need to know to get a job can be found and learned online. It is one of the few fields where people are regularly contributing time and information to provide you the resources you need to get into it yourself. It is likely also - though I don&amp;rsquo;t have the data for this - the only field where industry certifications (not degrees) are not a requirement for most jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And because of all this today so many people are willing to try their hand at coding. Having come from the same background (self-taught) this group &amp;ndash; new coders &amp;ndash; is my favorite. The excitement of solving something challenging is never replicated the same way as it is in someone who only a few days ago was a total programming n00b. These people know they like it but they might come across a point where they simply give up. And if you&amp;rsquo;ve ever hung out around new coders you find so many of them inevitably getting disheartened at how it&amp;rsquo;s a seemingly uphill struggle and they&amp;rsquo;re not really sure what&amp;rsquo;s going on anymore or that they spent hours learning the basics of Java but now what? Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s not enough building. Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s information overload and suddenly they&amp;rsquo;re overwhelmed. This is interesting to me. Despite all the resources that we have readily available, I find it perplexing that this is a field where even people who know they want to continue with coding end up getting disheartened so frequently. Having played around with a lot of &amp;ldquo;learn to code&amp;rdquo; services that offer tutorials or even, in some cases, a full-scale curriculum to become a programmer, I have some theories on this dissonance new coders encounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took three semesters of French in college. The first thing we did in our French class was just rote memorization - words for hello, welcome, good day, how are you, good bye, see you later, etc. We didn&amp;rsquo;t get to animals till like a month later. Didn&amp;rsquo;t get to everyday things like stationary till a month after that. Didn&amp;rsquo;t get to the rules of correct usage till three months in (note: our teacher was using the correct verbiage all along, but didn&amp;rsquo;t bog us down initially with explanations for why it had to be so.) As a result, it never felt like too much information and not once did it feel like what we were learning had no real immediate use. Imagine if one day we were being taught the words and then their multiple tenses and then how those tenses changed in a sentence structure, how those sentences could mean different things with just a few words changed, how this was all important before we even knew what the words really were. It would be so much useless information overload that someone new wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know what to do with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid one of the toys I used to occasionally play with was a &lt;a href=&#34;http://zephyrtoys.com/collections/mechanix&#34;&gt;Mechanix set&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s as close as you can get to teaching a little kid simple engineering skills. It is one of my favorite toys. When you open a Mechanix set manual, it&amp;rsquo;ll tell you what you need to do to build that particular set. Imagine instead giving a kid a Mechanix set and it has three different sized screws and instead of labeling them A, B, C in the manual, it has their exact sizes as referred to in the professional world. Then it goes on to explain why these screws are different sized and what that means, what the different steel plates are actually called, the correct way to hold a screwdriver, the right way to screw something. All of these details, though important in the real world, are useless to a kid who doesn&amp;rsquo;t have much knowledge about it initially. All they want to do is build something to play with it, not to understand the physics behind it. And yet this is what happens in most &amp;rsquo;learn to program&amp;rsquo; services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we learn a language we memorize things and only later learn how everything fits. This is very relevant. This is, in fact, how people should learn programming. Instead what ends up happening in programming tutorials is that people just keep learning the sizes of screws, the right way to hold a screwdriver, the multiple tenses and forms of different words - without ever actually being able to apply that knowledge to anything directly relevant to them. I think this is where the real dissonance occurs. When someone realizes that the tutorial they were following just spent a whole weekend teaching them the Javascript language so now they can write a Fibonacci series in the console, no questions asked, but they aren&amp;rsquo;t sure how this helps them build a website, it&amp;rsquo;s not likely that they&amp;rsquo;re going to go around looking for a new tutorial with enthusiasm. It&amp;rsquo;s more likely they&amp;rsquo;ll get bogged down and eventually maybe revisit it again at a later stage (if at all). Not saying all of this isn&amp;rsquo;t important, it is, but this is likely not why the person was interested in programming in the first place. They probably just wanted to see what they could build with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it seems to me that the problem with a lot of these tutorials is that they teach the rules of the language before telling people what the words are, what they can do, and how they can be used right &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;. This is all more important to a beginner than the in-depth stuff. When we learned the French words for hello, good morning, how are you, and good bye we were able to use them immediately. We walked in the next day and everyone said Bonjour instead of Hello. If we&amp;rsquo;d learned the words for cat and dog in the first class, we would have remembered them, sure, but we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know what to do with that knowledge. You just need more context to use cat/dog in a sentence. And so, on the first day, it just wasn&amp;rsquo;t directly relevant. Hello was relevant. It could be used immediately. It didn&amp;rsquo;t require knowing anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;]&lt;img src=&#34;images/171.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; Every new programmer goes through this phase.[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a lot of time looking for something like this and I think &lt;a href=&#34;http://freecodecamp.com/&#34;&gt;Freecodecamp&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://teamtreehouse.com&#34;&gt;Team Treehouse&lt;/a&gt; are the two that tend to come close to what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to articulate. I&amp;rsquo;m not a very good video learner (I like reading more) but every now and then I&amp;rsquo;ve used Treehouse to recall something I&amp;rsquo;d learned earlier. And it helps that a lot of their stuff is very industry relevant (dev tools, etc.) Similarly, Freecodecamp is something that provides just enough knowledge to help you build a project. Their strongest aspect is the near 24/7 online community that is there to help anyone stuck. In both cases, at the end of the day, you&amp;rsquo;re learning to build things before you know how to build things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you want to paint a room, you learn just enough about painting to get the job done. What kind of brush you need, what kind of paint, how to move the brush. You don&amp;rsquo;t sit through a class of aesthetics and color theory simply to paint a room. This practice of knowing &lt;em&gt;just enough&lt;/em&gt; is what I think can bridge the gap between learning and building, and maybe, just maybe, remove that early dissonance new coders face. If a service is able to master the right balance between imparting knowledge and providing rote instructions to build something interesting, they&amp;rsquo;ll be able to provide real value in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misadventures in Creativity</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/misadventures-in-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/misadventures-in-creativity/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as not to be the martyred slave of routine, plan adventure, plan pleasure, plan pandemonium, as you wish; but plan, plan secretly and without respite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Frisson/comments/2yndui/text_plan_secretly_and_without_respite_from/&#34;&gt;Full quote&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year or two ago I came across this quote in an email and had one of those rare moments where a few words seem to explain vividly a strong characteristic of yours. In this case, it is the simple pleasure of planning. I make plans for everything. Not terribly detailed project-management plans but simple grounded frameworks. If I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of a new project/idea I&amp;rsquo;ll inevitably start breaking it down on paper. Eventually I&amp;rsquo;ll plan out the steps and the details to reach the end. This is just how I think. It&amp;rsquo;s almost a natural habit and I do this for nearly everything - sometimes even grocery shopping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015, despite a lot of things having &lt;a href=&#34;https://axkhazan.wordpress.com/2016/01/08/towards-a-year-of-collaborations/&#34;&gt;happened&lt;/a&gt;, I was also fairly lazy. I got comfortable in a lot of aspects of my life, worked less hard, and generally didn&amp;rsquo;t take on as many new projects as I would have before (in college). I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of time to think about this. In some ways, I consider it a deserved lazy year, having gotten a job right out of college and having finally slowed down for a bit, but at the same time, I find myself most comfortable when I&amp;rsquo;m busy - doing things, building things, or even just planning things. And also, a year is a &lt;em&gt;really long time&lt;/em&gt; to be lazy and not taking on any new challenges. So I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of time to think about that as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did most of the filtering of my thoughts in the weeks leading up to 2016 and into its first week and basically at one point ended up just picking the few broad things I wanted to focus on for this year. This is far from a new year&amp;rsquo;s resolution per se (though I don&amp;rsquo;t know why those get a bad rep*). It&amp;rsquo;s mostly just prioritizing for the year what I want to focus on, what I want to spend time doing, and what I&amp;rsquo;ve come to realize over the years is what keeps me happy. On the contrary, I&amp;rsquo;ve also had a lot of time to think about what doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for me. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to identify where I fall short in the projects I&amp;rsquo;ve started but never completed and what the triggers for those shortcomings were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the the qualities I dislike about myself is the near extreme curiosity that turns into &lt;a href=&#34;https://axkhazan.wordpress.com/2016/01/12/the-semi-serious-proust-questionnaire/&#34;&gt;distractions&lt;/a&gt;. It has ended up in me having a folder named &lt;em&gt;Drafts&lt;/em&gt; on my desktop and countless unfinished code branches languishing abandoned in some kind of git void. This is kind of embarrassing. Actually, it&amp;rsquo;s even more embarrassing to announce a project and then have it relegated for eternity in some kind of computer netherworld, never to be seen again. So, disclaimer: I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ll stick to all the goals, though I&amp;rsquo;m certainly aiming for that - nights and weekends in full tow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I cannot deny that all of these failed attempts and joyous explorations sparked through distractions have also led me eventually to where I am today - still planing, with an ever shorter list of priorities. Almost like having one less route to test each time you wander. All of those side-roads of deviation from then-current projects allowed me to figure out over time &amp;ndash; and slightly better each day &amp;ndash; as to what it is I really like doing. Wandering does, eventually, bring you home. In my case, though, it did require looking at all the things I&amp;rsquo;d given up on mid-way and somehow accepting that this was stuff I might never return to one day, any day &amp;ndash; so, in a way, a wasted product. Otherwise everything would become a priority and, as a friend used to say, when everything is a priority nothing is a priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here I am again planning out my misadventures in creativity. I decided I was going to read 24 books this year which, most &lt;em&gt;readers&lt;/em&gt; would attest, is an awfully low number. But I&amp;rsquo;m trying this year to read better, slower, and a mix of genres. Having all those constraints in place, if I can make it past 24, I&amp;rsquo;ll be more than happy. But two books a month seems to be ideal pace for slow reading. And I&amp;rsquo;m already through with a book and a half. So I seem to be doing okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of reading, another project I want to do is to write a dystopian story. I&amp;rsquo;ve almost never been a fan of dystopian stories because I&amp;rsquo;ve never been able to relate to them (I tend towards realism quite a bit). So I figured I&amp;rsquo;d try to write one myself that incorporated a sort of realist dystopia that I would have enjoyed reading. I only have a general vague idea of its rules and landscapes that I&amp;rsquo;ve been tossing around in my head on and off for about two years now and I finally feel like I need to write it now before it escapes me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully some of these will iron themselves out before I get distracted by cat videos. But more later on the details for all the things I&amp;rsquo;ve got in mind that I&amp;rsquo;d like to see through to the finish this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*One of the fundamental reasons why I like new year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions, whether or not people keep them, is because they offer us a chance to reflect on what we want to achieve and, most importantly, what we believe we can achieve. It is absurd that people hate on such resolutions despite collectively feeling, even believing, that they can be better than their current self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quote is from a book on Anarchy. I haven&amp;rsquo;t read it, but I find it fascinating nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning a City Again</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/learning-a-city-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/learning-a-city-again/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids=&amp;ldquo;1127,1128,1129&amp;rdquo; type=&amp;ldquo;slideshow&amp;rdquo; link=&amp;ldquo;file&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was last in Delhi (a little over 2 years ago) I was walking around in the Ballimaran area of Delhi-6. It is chaotic, smelly, extremely overcrowded, and full of delicious food. I was with my cousin and we had overlapping but tangential agendas. Both of us were driven by wanting to get some authentic Delhi-6 street food. I also wanted to explore some old booksellers in Ballimaran and he had to get his glasses made &amp;ndash; which, in that area, is done pretty cheaply and with good enough quality. After having made our way through the many parathas and &lt;em&gt;dahi balle&lt;/em&gt; and the countless kulfis and jalebis, we finally went back to pick up his glasses. The sun was setting and we were there at an opportune time - it was Ramadan and people were about to break their fast. Ballimaran is close to Jama Masjid and so the &lt;em&gt;iftar&lt;/em&gt; preparations there were in full-throttle mode. After a while of retracing our steps to the glasses store (it is easy to get lost there even as a seasoned veteran of those lanes) and narrowly avoiding rickshaws rocketing by, the sun was finally down, the streets were lit up, and people everywhere were offering anyone a seat to join them in breaking their fast together. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that if I would have just walked up to street vendors and asked for food they would have given it for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we got to the store, we were told by the owner that he had &amp;lsquo;upgraded&amp;rsquo; the lens in the glasses and put a &amp;lsquo;better&amp;rsquo; one on than the one he had promised, however it was going to cost us a little more. (This seems to happen a lot around here.) We refused, and he nudged a little further all the while bringing the &amp;rsquo;extra&amp;rsquo; cost down slowly until my cousin finally agreed to an amount, both parties only half-satisfied with the negotiations. The owner was talking to us this whole while but what I hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed was that when we had walked in he had left his meal midway (the Ramadan fast that he was also breaking) while the rest of his crew continued to eat. And then something interesting happened. After the passionate haggling the owner invited us to join them for food! We were stuffed but it also seemed rude to say no to such a generous offer, and he was more than enthusiastic about the offer, so it never felt like it was being done out formality. Besides, when was the last time a random shopkeeper invited you for a meal out of formality? And that too after having negotiated a price he didn&amp;rsquo;t seem satisfied with? We explained that while he was fixing the glasses we had been eating to our heart&amp;rsquo;s and stomach&amp;rsquo;s content. Eventually, he only let us off after we&amp;rsquo;d each had a &lt;em&gt;dhokla&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has become one of my favorite stories about Delhi-6 and Delhi in general, and now when I travel in the States, something I often think about en route is what it takes to really know a city. To truly understand a place, its people, and culture whether you&amp;rsquo;ve grown up there or just drove in from a thousand miles away. And over time I&amp;rsquo;ve slowly kind of wandered my way into some kind of an answer for it - to know a city one ought to know its markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t believe you can truly know a place without first having immersed yourself in what I call its &lt;em&gt;grunge.&lt;/em&gt; There&amp;rsquo;s a reason Delhi-6 and its surroundings are attractive - they&amp;rsquo;re the grunge of the city. Not necessarily the &amp;lsquo;dirty&amp;rsquo; but more so the rustic &amp;ndash; the vintage that managed to exist through time. The gritty bylanes where the energy of today meets the resilience of history, where traditions collide and coalesce into something beautiful that lies precariously between a sense of nostalgia and wonder. Where even someone who&amp;rsquo;s grown up in Delhi can walk in and feel momentarily transformed by the air. I have come to believe that it is only after having first witnessed the overwhelming sights, sounds, and smells of a local market of any place do you get to know what it&amp;rsquo;s all about. The beat of the street, the way the people interact, the rhythm of activity that may appear chaotic initially but often has a definite process all end up making the city. And often they&amp;rsquo;re what the city is really about. It&amp;rsquo;s no wonder that the &lt;em&gt;bazaars&lt;/em&gt; of Istanbul are famous tourist attractions. As Delhi-6 does for Delhi, the bazaars offer a different personality of the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To every city (I use the term &amp;lsquo;city&amp;rsquo; very loosely here but it can be any place) there are at least two sides, if not more. There is the side facing the exterior, the world per se - the tourist pull to the place. Then there is the side that is the city on a daily basis - the daily grind, the hustle, all the things that make up the mundane existence of life there - the city equivalent of the time-space gap between great events in history where seemingly nothing happens. But just as these time gaps in great events are really the catalysts to the great events, these seemingly mundane qualities of a city that contribute to its daily bustle are the hidden gems of visiting any new place for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I left Ballimaran late that evening after gorging on some biryani for dinner, I realized how little I had really known Delhi despite having lived there for most of my life. What I did find in those bustling streets in the company of good food and good people was that it was never too late to get to know a place again. That remains to this day one of my favorite memories from that summer in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chandni Chowk streets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.indianholiday.com/photo-gallery/delhi-gallery/delhi-tourist-attractions/markets-in-delhi/chandni-chowk/Chandni-Chowk-2-500.jpg&#34;&gt;http://www.indianholiday.com/photo-gallery/delhi-gallery/delhi-tourist-attractions/markets-in-delhi/chandni-chowk/Chandni-Chowk-2-500.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chandni Chowk food&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.new-delhi-hotels.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Chandni-Chowk-Food.jpg&#34;&gt;http://www.new-delhi-hotels.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Chandni-Chowk-Food.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nai Sarak books&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ixigo-com-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t&#34;&gt;https://ixigo-com-res.cloudinary.com/image/upload/t&lt;/a&gt;_large,f_auto/nai-sarak-images-photos-51cd2a7046054ad777000001.jpg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>