<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dignity on Ayushman Khazanchi</title>
    <link>https://akzn.me/tags/dignity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dignity on Ayushman Khazanchi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 14:10:20 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akzn.me/tags/dignity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Can You Imagine?</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/can-you-imagine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 14:10:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/can-you-imagine/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1049&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;250&amp;rdquo;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/kalman_principlesofuncertainty2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/kalman_principlesofuncertainty2.png?w=194&#34; alt=&#34;Image of a page from Maira Kalman&amp;amp;rsquo;s The Principles of Uncertainty&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Maira Kalman - The Principles of Uncertainty[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you imagine being so alone, so helpless that you&amp;rsquo;re stuck in the middle-divider of a busy road on an electric wheelchair with your batteries bust? I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even picture something like this happening until I saw it happen to someone today. It rattled me a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the time of our lives that we spend on growing and building our community and then we go out alone. On my way back from work I cross a four lane road that, around office rush-hour time, is bumper to bumper traffic. Bad enough that cars frequently spill into the box trying to make it past the traffic lights. There&amp;rsquo;s only about ten seconds of a walk signal on this crossing. It&amp;rsquo;s not bad, can be done easily enough even if all you&amp;rsquo;ve got are jello-legs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, though, while walking up to the intersection, I saw an old man on one of those electric wheelchairs stuck in the middle of the road fiddling with the controls on the right handle. Initially I just glanced at him and didn&amp;rsquo;t pay much heed (the limits of our attention, right?). It really only struck me that there was even a problem when I was already halfway through crossing the road and the guy still hadn&amp;rsquo;t moved, was still fiddling with the controls. (There&amp;rsquo;s a fairly decent-sized divider in the middle of the road so he wasn&amp;rsquo;t literally on the road or in danger.) Since I was crossing from the other side, I decided I&amp;rsquo;d cross back and help him out (that darned ten second timer) but when I got to his side there was already a student who, having crossed up to the same point as the old man and mid-way having noticed his immobility, asked him if there was a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1048&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;265&amp;rdquo;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/kalman11.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/kalman11.png?w=226&#34; alt=&#34;Image of a page from Maira Kalman&amp;amp;rsquo;s The Principles of Uncertainty&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Maira Kalman - The Principles of Uncertainty[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course there was. I watched from the other end &amp;ndash; though I couldn&amp;rsquo;t hear them over the traffic &amp;ndash; and I saw the old man, obviously feeling embarrassed, denying the offer of help as if it was just a simple thing he could brush off any minute. Like someone just made a mistake and soon things would be fine. Like the wheelchair was just playing games on him. Not a problem. But we drop all our walls when we honestly need, and want, genuine help. I&amp;rsquo;m glad the guy stuck around despite the old man initially declining his offer. He wheeled him over in the next ten second interval as I stood on the other side, the angst-ridden equivalent of helpless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other side, safer and what seemed to be a little bit relaxed, the man continued to fiddle with his controls, not acknowledging our presence. We didn&amp;rsquo;t mind. Life is hard enough. We stood around for a while unsure as to the extent of our responsibility. I asked eventually if we could call him a cab, but he refused. The student asked him if he could call someone who could pick him up. He refused. We looked at each other. Was there even someone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I eventually asked if it would work, foolishly hoping for some kind of emergency-battery mechanism or something to prevent exactly these situations. Now searching through the cords for something under the seat, he said it would. Confident, short answers. After a few minutes and a few remarks from the old man that he was fine, and obviously otherwise being of very little help, we decided to leave. What can you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked away a little heartbroken, a little disappointed that for all the money and all our information and all the apps and all the people around on the busiest street in town, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t get a man home, couldn&amp;rsquo;t get him to safely cross the road with dignity and without fear - without that thought that will now remain etched in his mind as he whizzes around - that someday his wheelchair might run out of juice, a wheel might get caught in a pothole (happened as he was pushed across road) or it might just flat-out breakdown. Or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s happened before. How else was he so sure it would work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I turned around after a few steps to check if he was still there but he wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>