<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on Ayushman Khazanchi</title>
    <link>https://akzn.me/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on Ayushman Khazanchi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akzn.me/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exit Series - Cultural Criticism</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/exit-series-cultural-criticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/exit-series-cultural-criticism/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One Saturday I find myself walking these streets that I have known intimately for almost 3 years now. 17th street leading to Locust leading to 18th to Sansom and eventually to Joseph Fox Books which is where I&amp;rsquo;m headed right now. This is a pretty elongated route to get to the bookstore from my place (I could cut at least 3 blocks). I prefer this way though, because it takes you by the edge of Rittenhouse park and &lt;em&gt;Parc&lt;/em&gt;, a lively French restaurant. I am not looking for anything in particular and I&amp;rsquo;m certainly averse to spending money on another book, but I like browsing the shelves and the desire to not be alone at home on this Saturday morning has propelled me here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the bookstore, I am listening in on a conversation between the staff and a prospective customer. They&amp;rsquo;re looking up Hilton Als&amp;rsquo; White Girls to understand what it&amp;rsquo;s about - the girl had inquired about it. &amp;ldquo;Cultural criticism&amp;rdquo; is what a cursory search on the internet brings up and the customer, probably looking for a summer beach-read and entirely dissuaded by the weight of the result, promptly shelves the book. I haven&amp;rsquo;t read it but know that &amp;ldquo;cultural criticism&amp;rdquo; barely does justice to the book. I wonder how Hilton Als feels about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I browse through some books on design and art &amp;ndash; genres I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in lately &amp;ndash; but since I didn&amp;rsquo;t come here to buy anything I end up leaving soon after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is part of &lt;a href=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/category/exit-series/&#34;&gt;Exit Series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 - Numbers and Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/2016-numbers-and-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/2016-numbers-and-thoughts/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Overall 2016 was a good year for me. Here&amp;rsquo;s some thoughts on stuff that happened and what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from all of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was by far the most demanding year I&amp;rsquo;ve had at work. I started the year off with accepting more responsibility (I was made the Team Lead for one our internal products) and that has turned out to be one of the most interesting learning experiences this year. This gave me an interesting glimpse into the organizational side of things and kind of forced me to start looking at the bigger picture of where our team was going. It also helped me improve some of my non-technical, organizational, skills like estimates, scope, and time management. More than anything it forced me to prioritize what I wanted to/had to devote my time towards, especially when it came to communication. Email still sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The negative effects of context-switching are something that are often talked about in the developer world. What is it? It&amp;rsquo;s when you&amp;rsquo;re working on one thing and are required to immediately put it aside and work on something else entirely, thereby interrupting the flow you were in. It might be a meeting that&amp;rsquo;s scheduled or it might be your boss asking you to deliver something else first. It happens, and until we get to a point where no manager ever requests you to immediately switch contexts and you never get scheduled for a random middle-of-the-day meeting ever, we&amp;rsquo;re just going to have to get better at it. Taking on more work has put me in a situation where more people need stuff from me. So I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself having to switch focus a lot this year. I&amp;rsquo;m still not great at it but something I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that helps is to make a short list of &amp;lsquo;pending/next items&amp;rsquo; on the task that you&amp;rsquo;re working on before you put it aside. This has helped me get into it faster when I do return to it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the code I wrote this year has been for work but I did start getting into Android near the end of the year so more to follow on that in the coming months. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to have more time this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Play&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I&amp;rsquo;m really happy about is that I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing a lot of football (soccer) again. I found a group that plays pickup on weekend mornings and I try to go most games. I found this group pretty late in the year (around August) and ended up playing in one of the leagues they had going from September to November. I also played my first sub-zero temperature game so that was fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve volunteered a lot more this year, especially teaching kids coding once a week. What I&amp;rsquo;ve learned is this: being a good teacher, with the right balance of strictness &amp;amp; fun, is really hard. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how quickly you realize this when you start teaching kids. I have a newfound respect for teachers. I&amp;rsquo;m a little unnerved by the amount of access really young kids have to screens but also amazed at how fast they learn how to use tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I&amp;rsquo;ve had some interesting interactions with people on really hard and touchy subjects – politics, race, privacy, the role of media vs. citizens etc. Most of these interactions happened in person and the general sentiment has been that the digital platforms we&amp;rsquo;ve built are no longer the grounds for intellectual discussion that we&amp;rsquo;d hoped they&amp;rsquo;d become. I still believe that they can be, but it is up to us to put forth the kind of discussions we want to have. Whether we simply propagate our beliefs or we actually seek to understand is something in our control and no amount of blaming an ecosystem is going to really change that. This is something I get more skeptical about everyday but there is still hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put traveling on a hiatus near the end of the year. I got a little disillusioned and tired of it and I want to take some time to understand what I want out of it before I start again. I&amp;rsquo;ve talked to a lot of people about why they travel and the general answer is to experience new cultures but new cultures are also available within a block&amp;rsquo;s distance. And with the current political climate it may actually help to connect with the cultures in our communities. Despite all this I did manage to go to 15 cities, mostly to see friends and families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Fun Numbers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mostly calculated all these off of memory - save for the books which Goodreads tracked &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/user/year_in_books/2016/5335295&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This has got me wondering if there&amp;rsquo;s an app to easily keep track of this&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table style=&#34;height: 246px;&#34; width=&#34;606&#34;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Books I read this year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Poems I added to a poetry collaboration &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/christutolo&#34;&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; and I started last year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Poems we added in total this year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;33&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;People I learned something from or had a good time with (caveat: only people I met in person this year and spent at least a few hours with)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Cities/places I visited&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Podcast finished (How I Built This, NPR)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;football matches played&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;7&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;1623,1661,1663,1666,1669,1670,1672&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misadventures in Creativity</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/misadventures-in-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/misadventures-in-creativity/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as not to be the martyred slave of routine, plan adventure, plan pleasure, plan pandemonium, as you wish; but plan, plan secretly and without respite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Frisson/comments/2yndui/text_plan_secretly_and_without_respite_from/&#34;&gt;Full quote&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year or two ago I came across this quote in an email and had one of those rare moments where a few words seem to explain vividly a strong characteristic of yours. In this case, it is the simple pleasure of planning. I make plans for everything. Not terribly detailed project-management plans but simple grounded frameworks. If I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of a new project/idea I&amp;rsquo;ll inevitably start breaking it down on paper. Eventually I&amp;rsquo;ll plan out the steps and the details to reach the end. This is just how I think. It&amp;rsquo;s almost a natural habit and I do this for nearly everything - sometimes even grocery shopping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015, despite a lot of things having &lt;a href=&#34;https://axkhazan.wordpress.com/2016/01/08/towards-a-year-of-collaborations/&#34;&gt;happened&lt;/a&gt;, I was also fairly lazy. I got comfortable in a lot of aspects of my life, worked less hard, and generally didn&amp;rsquo;t take on as many new projects as I would have before (in college). I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of time to think about this. In some ways, I consider it a deserved lazy year, having gotten a job right out of college and having finally slowed down for a bit, but at the same time, I find myself most comfortable when I&amp;rsquo;m busy - doing things, building things, or even just planning things. And also, a year is a &lt;em&gt;really long time&lt;/em&gt; to be lazy and not taking on any new challenges. So I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of time to think about that as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did most of the filtering of my thoughts in the weeks leading up to 2016 and into its first week and basically at one point ended up just picking the few broad things I wanted to focus on for this year. This is far from a new year&amp;rsquo;s resolution per se (though I don&amp;rsquo;t know why those get a bad rep*). It&amp;rsquo;s mostly just prioritizing for the year what I want to focus on, what I want to spend time doing, and what I&amp;rsquo;ve come to realize over the years is what keeps me happy. On the contrary, I&amp;rsquo;ve also had a lot of time to think about what doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for me. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to identify where I fall short in the projects I&amp;rsquo;ve started but never completed and what the triggers for those shortcomings were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the the qualities I dislike about myself is the near extreme curiosity that turns into &lt;a href=&#34;https://axkhazan.wordpress.com/2016/01/12/the-semi-serious-proust-questionnaire/&#34;&gt;distractions&lt;/a&gt;. It has ended up in me having a folder named &lt;em&gt;Drafts&lt;/em&gt; on my desktop and countless unfinished code branches languishing abandoned in some kind of git void. This is kind of embarrassing. Actually, it&amp;rsquo;s even more embarrassing to announce a project and then have it relegated for eternity in some kind of computer netherworld, never to be seen again. So, disclaimer: I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ll stick to all the goals, though I&amp;rsquo;m certainly aiming for that - nights and weekends in full tow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I cannot deny that all of these failed attempts and joyous explorations sparked through distractions have also led me eventually to where I am today - still planing, with an ever shorter list of priorities. Almost like having one less route to test each time you wander. All of those side-roads of deviation from then-current projects allowed me to figure out over time &amp;ndash; and slightly better each day &amp;ndash; as to what it is I really like doing. Wandering does, eventually, bring you home. In my case, though, it did require looking at all the things I&amp;rsquo;d given up on mid-way and somehow accepting that this was stuff I might never return to one day, any day &amp;ndash; so, in a way, a wasted product. Otherwise everything would become a priority and, as a friend used to say, when everything is a priority nothing is a priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here I am again planning out my misadventures in creativity. I decided I was going to read 24 books this year which, most &lt;em&gt;readers&lt;/em&gt; would attest, is an awfully low number. But I&amp;rsquo;m trying this year to read better, slower, and a mix of genres. Having all those constraints in place, if I can make it past 24, I&amp;rsquo;ll be more than happy. But two books a month seems to be ideal pace for slow reading. And I&amp;rsquo;m already through with a book and a half. So I seem to be doing okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of reading, another project I want to do is to write a dystopian story. I&amp;rsquo;ve almost never been a fan of dystopian stories because I&amp;rsquo;ve never been able to relate to them (I tend towards realism quite a bit). So I figured I&amp;rsquo;d try to write one myself that incorporated a sort of realist dystopia that I would have enjoyed reading. I only have a general vague idea of its rules and landscapes that I&amp;rsquo;ve been tossing around in my head on and off for about two years now and I finally feel like I need to write it now before it escapes me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully some of these will iron themselves out before I get distracted by cat videos. But more later on the details for all the things I&amp;rsquo;ve got in mind that I&amp;rsquo;d like to see through to the finish this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*One of the fundamental reasons why I like new year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions, whether or not people keep them, is because they offer us a chance to reflect on what we want to achieve and, most importantly, what we believe we can achieve. It is absurd that people hate on such resolutions despite collectively feeling, even believing, that they can be better than their current self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quote is from a book on Anarchy. I haven&amp;rsquo;t read it, but I find it fascinating nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Life Akhil Sharma</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/family-life-akhil-sharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/family-life-akhil-sharma/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/family_life.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/family_life.jpg?w=200&#34; alt=&#34;Image of book&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you even begin to write about a book that is so painfully honest that it can be tender and heartbreaking in the same sentence. In its most mundane parts. This is the story of Ajay growing up envying his older brother, Birju, in every sense of the word. Once when visiting their grandparents Birju is the one to inform them that their father has sent tickets for the family to emigrate to America. Immediately Ajay is in a state of resentment for not having been the &amp;lsquo;bearer&amp;rsquo; of this good news. Everything Birju does seems flawless and infinitely wise to Ajay. But an event that renders Birju entirely disabled changes their lives forever. It&amp;rsquo;s comforting to put the book in that box - to call it a story of loss and dealing with that loss, but it turns out to be so much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot here is simply of time passing. We grow with Ajay and his thoughts. Living with a person with a disability is a full-time job in many cases, one that we don&amp;rsquo;t automatically realize. But what happens when that person is your older brother who you used to envy? What happens when everything you ever wanted &amp;ndash; to be the wiser, cooler, more successful brother &amp;ndash; suddenly come to fruition at a cost you could never imagine? This is as much a coming-of-age story as it is about the burden of responsibility, about what we do for the ones we love. There&amp;rsquo;s a few parts where Ajay talks to God (he&amp;rsquo;s conversing with himself) and we learn that love is not always about blind devotion. That we all have to find our way back to it constantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m ashamed,&amp;rdquo; I said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;About what?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That after the accident, I was glad I might become an only child.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everybody thinks strange thoughts,&amp;rdquo; God said. &amp;ldquo;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you think something.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When I was walking around in the schoolyard and you asked if I would switch places with Birju, I thought, &lt;em&gt;No.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a constant underlying guilt that Ajay &amp;ndash; the narrator &amp;ndash; lives with as he grows with his brother, trying to learn how to love him again. It is so painfully honest. I&amp;rsquo;ve often wondered where this capacity to love endlessly come from - where one spends their days caring for their own without any expectation of reward or return. Surely there is a sense of duty here, but in that duty, is there always some form of love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akhil Sharma puts it succinctly through Ajay&amp;rsquo;s lens (and often the other family members who are equally battling their own demons). We find the boy often asking himself why things aren&amp;rsquo;t just normal in his life. Anyone who has spent caring for the disabled, the mentally ill, or even their very old grandparents knows this feeling of wanting to not care for a little while. But we don&amp;rsquo;t like acknowledging this thought, for it is a duty, and acknowledging it would render us weak. We see this time and again in this autobiographical novel - the clash between love and duty on the one hand and on the other the desire to simply walk away from it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike most novels that deal with some kind of loss or grief, this isn&amp;rsquo;t some earth-shattering story. This is the sharp pain of a needle-stab that you only feel when it&amp;rsquo;s slowly being extricated. That feeling is already inside all of us, Family Life just manages to make its presence known. It showed me that one can live with loss and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be perfect. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t require perfect composition and unconditional love or even eternal devotion. It requires that we come together and strengthen each other when the road gets rocky. It requires that we put aside our &amp;lsquo;strange thoughts&amp;rsquo; and find ways to love again. It shows that love has to be cultivated, and not found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I think about loss, it&amp;rsquo;s usually about death. I read Wave, where Deraniyagala lost her whole family, and I thought this is what loss is about. But what struck me is that the disability that Birju has is an even more profound kind of loss. He&amp;rsquo;s there, and he&amp;rsquo;s alive, but he&amp;rsquo;s practically in coma and now you have to care for him for the rest of your life. (There&amp;rsquo;s even a point where the mother describes his state as being in a coma, because simply saying he&amp;rsquo;s brain-damaged doesn&amp;rsquo;t elicit as much sympathy in others.) Disability can, at times, be a greater pain to deal with than anything else and we all ought to do more and do better to acknowledge and understand this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this is not all about grief and loss. There are tender moments of communities helping each other out, of acceptance of our fragile selves, of growing teenagers exploring love, and what it means to be vulnerable. I wanted to pick out a few quotes from this book that show this aspect that despite all odds we still do the routine things - we still want to love and be loved, we still want to find success, and we still oscillate between wanting to be better and wanting to give up. But it&amp;rsquo;s nearly impossible since there are so many little moments like these that I eventually stopped marking them. They are the real gems of this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A phone call cost ten cents a minute if made after nine o&amp;rsquo;clock at night. To save money, we spoke every other day. On the days we didn&amp;rsquo;t, I would call her room at nine and hang up after one ring. She would then do the same, and this was how we said we loved each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pick it up if you can. This is a book for the shelf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bathroom Jean Philippe Toussaint</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/the-bathroom-jean-philippe-toussaint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/the-bathroom-jean-philippe-toussaint/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/the_bathroom.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/the_bathroom.jpg?w=194&#34; alt=&#34;Image of the book cover&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have just finished a rather perplexing book. Perplexing in the way that only French things can seem perplexing to those not well versed with the deeper intricacies of the French culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bathroom is about an unnamed narrator in Paris who spends his days living in his bathroom. In his desire to achieve extreme immobility, he goes over the principles behind trying such a thing in different ways. The book is filled with many arguments for such a case, one of which is the narrator trying to understand how best to watch the rainfall. Eventually, he deduces it best to &amp;lsquo;watch&amp;rsquo; the rainfall by looking at rain in two ways - one, by staring at one fixed point and watching all the rain fall through it, and two, by fixing the gaze upon one drop of rain and following it through to its combining with the ground. In all this, Edmondsson (his wife? girlfriend?*) and the two Polish painters in his house (who end up not actually doing any painting but returning later to randomly skin some octopuses in his house?) enable his desire to remain in the bathroom. There is not much more to the overall story except that one day he receives an invite to the Austrian embassy and he realizes that &amp;ldquo;perhaps it was not very healthy, at age twenty-seven going on twenty-nine, to live more or less shut up in a bathtub.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what to make of this book. The writing is good, even great at certain parts, but there&amp;rsquo;s a point where the narrator, accompanying his doctor and his doctor&amp;rsquo;s wife to a tennis match, stares into a mirror at his dimly-lit face and asks himself: &amp;ldquo;what was I doing here?&amp;rdquo; There were multiple points in the book where I had the same question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if Edmondsson was the wife or the girlfriend because the narrator at one point refers to her as his wife but the summary on the back cover refers to Edmondsson as his girlfriend. Not sure if this is all an elaborate joke at this point, or that I just didn&amp;rsquo;t get the point of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weight of Some Books</title>
      <link>https://akzn.me/blog/the-weight-of-some-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akzn.me/blog/the-weight-of-some-books/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1013&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;1200&amp;rdquo;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://akzn.me/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/2014-11-02-00-06-321.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/2014-11-02-00-06-321.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Principles of Uncertainty, by Maira Kalman&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Principles of Uncertainty, by Maira Kalman[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever found yourself picking up a new book without knowing much about it, leafing through the first few pages, maybe even a chapter, and suddenly unable to stop reading? It seldom happens to me to a severe extent. I find that, even given all the availability of time and comfort, I no longer read a book in one sitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, a few weeks ago, having just finished brunch with an old friend, I found myself with cancelled plans on a beautiful Saturday afternoon. So I ventured into a Barnes and Noble, picked up Maira Kalman’s The Principles of Uncertainty, found a plush couch in a coffee bar nearby, and began reading. I started around 2 pm and finished the book by 11 pm that night. Between the first page and the last, I drank entirely too much coffee, changed cafes twice, realized how uncomfortable park benches are, and rode a bus back home. The last time I finished a book in one sitting was a year and a half ago in a campus cafe reading Novecento by Alessandro Baricco. In both cases, I was hooked, though for entirely different reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve long felt that the books we truly love are the ones that hold a mirror to ourselves but show us a side of ourselves we weren’t quite able to discern before. Almost like learning who you are through someone else. Even then, Kalman’s work doesn’t tend to fit this simplistic idea. It’s hard to describe this book — if you can even call it that, given it’s equal parts words and art. It’s simply a wonderful journey through Kalman’s mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heart breaks. Someone does and does not go mad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How can I tell you everything that is in my heart?” begins Kalman. As the book proceeds, we’re given a brief history of the extinction of the dodo, informed about the life and fate of various Russian authors (and prominent thinkers), Kalman’s family and their background, about hats, suitcases, and pieces of furniture that Kalman has encountered. This is not, as it may initially seem, some arbitrary collection of information. It is precisely how we encounter life, jumping from thought to thought, place to place, as a means to avoid matters of discomfort, or importance, towards diversions that please us momentarily. Take, for example, the mid-book detour to Paris in order to avoid dealing with philosophy, or more serious and pressing issues such as Nietzsche’s mustache. It is also very funny — something this book does quite well given it tends to discuss war, death, and philosophy, all within a page or two of discussing hats and dodos. It is sometimes incredibly mind-bending realizing how fully aware Kalman is of her environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also, by far, one of the most profound books I’ve read in a long, long while, even with all its deviations and contradictions and thoughtless-thoughts that end up stringing themselves together to form a mirror on our existence. There are questions of life and death, of war, of life in war, and in the gray areas that arise from conflicts between the self and our larger role in the world. At one point, quite clearly irked at having just had a white shirt stained standing somewhere in Tel Aviv, Israel, Kalman poses the question, “Is there room for pettiness during a war?” At another point, she acknowledges that she has “many questions but no patience to think things through.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone is going forward, and everyone is behind everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finished reading the book, I thought against writing about it, not because I didn’t want to share it with people but mostly because I didn’t think any description I could come up with regards the book would do it any sufficient justice. I finished it, put it aside and, over the next few weeks, occasionally went back to it flicking to a random page and seeing what came up. It was one of these random page-flipping moments that convinced me to write about it. On an otherwise blank white page were two handwritten lines mentioning Freud’s belief that “what we say means something. And must be spoken.” Below it lies a paragraph on Wittgenstein’s humorous counter-belief. but I’ll let you pick up the book for that one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>